<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>saffron huang</title>
    <link>https://saffronh.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on saffron huang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2016-19 &lt;a href=&#39;https://github.com/siegerts/hugo-theme-basic&#39;&gt;Hugo Theme Basic&lt;/a&gt;.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="https://saffronh.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>So, I Almost Drowned</title>
      <link>https://saffronh.github.io/post/so-i-almost-drowned/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saffronh.github.io/post/so-i-almost-drowned/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I almost drowned in a sensory deprivation flotation tank when my hair was sucked into the filtration system. I was not told about much of the actual float procedure nor the existence of an emergency button, which I couldn’t reach anyway. No one was meant to check in on me. This is an absurd horror story about losing agency to an automated system featuring, as I discovered, no real contingency plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I turned 23 recently. For my birthday, a few of my friends gave me a float voucher as I’d mentioned an interest in trying it. It’s the kind of unusual sensory experience that piques my curiosity. But at $100 NZD for an hour-long session, it’s also a potential source of buyer’s remorse that I’d prefer someone else pay for. A birthday, I figure, is an excuse for frivolity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the only employee on duty, let’s call her Anna, was stepping me through the procedure, I asked her, “Should I tie my hair up?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“No, don’t worry about it,” she responded. She told me about the extreme salinity of the water, and that there was a blue button in the tank to turn the lights on inside&amp;mdash;but that in the interests of full relief and relaxation, it was best to lay in complete darkness. I was instructed to shower before getting in the tank, and as I was doing so I once more casually thought about tying my hair up. I decided against it, since I was told to shower again afterwards and it would be a hassle to untie wet hair. Anyway, there seemed to be no benefit to it, as espoused by Anna’s response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got out of the shower and put the earplugs in, as she’d advised, to keep the water out of my ears. I dipped a foot into the tank, testing the warmth of the water. I could almost taste traces of salt in the air&amp;mdash;apparently, there were 5kgs of epsom salt dissolved in this small pod. This would be more than enough to keep me afloat. Anna had told me not to touch my face, and particularly not my eyes; the heavy sting of the salt would quickly spoil any attempt at tranquility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Music would play for the first ten minutes and the last five minutes of the hour-long float. The initial music was intended to relax me; the music at the end would serve as the signal that my time was up. As I laid down in the water, I pulled the lid of the tank down. The lights both inside and outside the tank slowly blinked off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feeling both curious and skeptical, I made mental note of what I was experiencing and how I was feeling. I could move my limbs around entirely frictionlessly and weightlessly, so I did that. I tried pushing my arms down and felt the resistance of the water’s salinity. I lightly paddled my hands and felt waves of water sweep up my body, brushing my face. I couldn’t yet tell if the muscles in my neck or shoulders were any looser. I tried to meditate on my breath. As my eyes adjusted to the dark, sparks danced across my vision, and faded. (Unfortunately, I can’t report actual hallucinations, which some people experience.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could barely hear the music through both the earplugs and the water it kept out. I planned to text my friends afterwards with jokes about returning to the womb, slipping around a watery cocoon in absolute darkness and, once the ten minutes of music ended, absolute silence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s common to fall asleep during a float. I read the business’s online FAQ, where they reassure floaters-to-be that they wouldn’t drown if they fell asleep. The salts would keep them afloat, and if they were to turn over the water would immediately wake them. I really lost my sense of time in there, but I think I became sleepy and hypnagogic perhaps 30 minutes in, and&amp;mdash;although I made some attempt at staying alert&amp;mdash;I started drifting in and out of wakefulness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some point I felt a mild tugging sensation on my scalp. Hmm, weird. I thought it was just my head bumping against the side of the tank, but I felt around with my hand and found that a good chunk of my hair had become pulled into a head-height vent at the top of the tank. This was not a few strands; it was, if compressed, a coin-sized diameter of hair being pulled, leaving increasingly little length from the skin of my scalp, and increasingly little freedom of movement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fuck.&lt;/em&gt; I had to get loose. My face was only an inch above water. Maybe if I pulled with all my body’s might, I could free myself. Adrenaline surged; I tugged as hard as I could, and in the process I flipped over and swallowed a mouthful of disgustingly salty water. My eyes stung, hard. When I eventually was able to come up for air and still myself, I spluttered and spat out water, and told myself that my first priority was to keep my face up, and stay calm. Drowning in a flotation tank was not going to be the way I died.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My hair was so solidly ensnared in the vent that there was no way I could pull the strands loose, or break them off. A mere bundle of keratin is unreasonably strong. I tried to tie the rest of my hair up with the hairband on my wrist, bunching it in an attempt to prevent more from being sucked up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d seen a red button near the opening of the tank. No one had told me what it was, but I figured that was the emergency button. (Later, Anna told me that it doesn’t work, anyway. Even later, her manager disputed that claim, saying that the emergency button does work. As you can see, things are maximally confusing.) However, as I was glued to the other end of the tank, I couldn’t reach it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I yelled into pitch black.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HELP!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrenched away the earplugs, trying to hear anything. No response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I kicked, and managed to get the lid of the tank up a little bit. I told myself I just needed to hold on until she came to check on me, but I had no idea how long that might be. I couldn’t see, I couldn’t hear, I was floating in water and unable to free myself. I have something of a phobia of drowning; every time I’ve had to swim in deep bodies of water (e.g. for “fun” school activities), I’ve been unduly anxious. I was very aware of the perimeter of water partially submerging my face, ebbing up and down. I tried not to hyperventilate&amp;mdash;not endangering my breath was very important. I felt entirely vulnerable, and entirely terrified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I yelled a few more times, and finally I heard her anxious voice at the door. “Are you alright?” “NO?!?! I’m trapped!” Eventually, “Can I come in?” &lt;em&gt;What the fuck, please come in!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She was on the phone with her manager as she tried to figure out what to do. I told her to get scissors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’m shaking,” she said as she worked on cutting through my hair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I sat up and coughed heavily, trying to expel the water from my system. When I looked in the mirror, my hair looked like it was done in a giant messy bun at the crown. And that was the part that &lt;em&gt;wasn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; tied up (in fact, I&amp;rsquo;d only managed to tie a small amount with the hairband). It was that tangled. My eyes were salt-swollen and red, and the drying crystals had started to cake my face. I felt so sad, and so relieved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You told me not to tie my hair up!” was the first thing I blurted when I eventually came out to the front desk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Well yeah, you didn’t have to!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was stunned. “What?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Didn’t you hear the music?” Anna asked me as a response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently, the five minutes of music at the end and a voice instructing me to leave the tank should have been my cue to get out. I also learned that a filtration system automatically starts to pump after the music ends. But with the earplugs in as instructed, and having either fallen asleep or been in a state of hypnagogia, I couldn’t tell her whether the music had actually played or not. Even if it had played, the initial music had been so faint, I doubted its ability to wake anyone. Again, it’s common to fall asleep in a float tank, as it is deliberately relaxing. In fact, some people &lt;a href=&#34;https://slate.com/human-interest/2015/11/i-slept-all-night-in-a-sensory-deprivation-tank.html&#34;&gt;intentionally sleep in one at night&lt;/a&gt;. I’m not a heavy sleeper, either; I never miss a morning alarm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They programmed the tank to start the filtration immediately, without effective alarms, or checking that I’d actually gotten out. There exist flotation tanks with sensors, which could have automatically delayed the filtration process until no movement is detected; at the very least, a gentle knock on the door informing me that my time was up doesn’t seem much to ask. Anna said that she’d noticed I wasn’t out after my session and hadn’t turned the shower on yet, but thought nothing of checking on me to see if things were going okay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The manager called me tonight, which was illuminating. I found out that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had not been told that there was a correct orientation to lie down in. My head should have been near the opening of the tank, but it was towards the end with the vent. (Although it seems from Google Images that people have laid in it both ways.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I should have been told that the emergency button existed and how to use it. I’d only inferred it from seeing the red button.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I should have been walked through the entire flotation system, and been informed that the filtration pipes would start after my session ended; I was not.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The music at the end is supposed to be a soft, gentle awakening, not a loud alarm, which confirmed my suspicions. Especially if they also advise putting in earplugs, I think they should have mentioned that it might be hard to hear.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In her experience, 1 of 50 people sleep through the music and have stayed in there once the filtration starts. I assume that none of them have gone in the wrong way or had long hair. If they knew that people do sleep through the music, I wonder why it was not procedural to check on me. I had to yell multiple times to get any attention.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She told me that she would run tests on whether the music had been loud enough in my specific tank, and placed a lot of blame on Anna, the only employee present, who had worked there for only two months. She was clearly very concerned about her business; as a result, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to know whether the procedures that she claimed are normally followed are actually in practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems like multiple parts of the system were ill-considered, or simply collapsed. I was incredulous. I’m the type of exacting user who carefully remembers and follows instructions, I was entirely sober, and I have no health issues unlike many of their other customers. According to the manager, people with PTSD, anxiety, claustrophobic tendencies, and so on come in to float, often looking to heal. If something like this had happened to one of them, they’d probably be much more traumatised, or worse, dead. There are plenty more creative ways that this could have gone wrong. My own “missteps&amp;quot; were not particularly crazy: I wasn’t informed that there was a “correct” way to get in the tank, and I wasn’t woken up by the music. Two laughably mundane mishaps were enough to create a potentially life-threatening situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most important thing at the moment is processing my emotions, but I can’t help but point out the more general relevance of this experience, which is also a very personal issue for me. Implicitly and explicitly, I was asked to trust&amp;mdash;and did trust&amp;mdash;the interlocking system of technology and humans that constituted this sensory deprivation tank experience. It is intended for my benefit, and I’m advised to surrender and relax inside it. Many more vulnerable people look to this to try to heal from physical or mental distress, trusting themselves to the process. This is a particularly poignant example of how everyday, as we interact with the designs and impressive feats of engineering that constitute our world, our trust is asked for and necessarily given. As users meandering through, we can’t know it all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the products of human agency tend to evade human control. This was clearly not an intended outcome, but it was certainly a foreseeable one. What is more egregious is that there weren’t multiple, layered contingency plans for failure modes, foreseeable or not. Okay, I wasn’t told about the emergency button, and I wasn’t able to hit it. Even if I don’t call for help myself, there should be someone checking in. It’s an hour-long float in water in an utterly isolated, enclosed space, an experience new to many&amp;mdash;if someone had an anxiety attack and couldn’t find the button in the dark, there were no safety systems to catch them. &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important side note:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; Both anxiety and ketamine cause dissociation, and ketamine use is known to kill people in sensory deprivation tanks. Please be very careful about floating if you’re prone to dissociation, and definitely don’t take ketamine and try this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had consented to be stripped of my senses inside an unfamiliar apparatus, but that was consent based on the assurance that they knew what they were doing. That degree of trust, the belief that it was a controlled relinquishment of autonomy, made the fall all the worse. I had no idea that the preprogrammed agency of the flotation tank would take all of my own agency away from me. After I got out, I cried and held Anna’s hand, telling her how scared I was of the possibility that she wouldn’t come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m still a little in shock. The lingering burn of the salt water is still in my throat, the top of my head is tender, and my neck hurts in new and strange ways. My hair looks surprisingly normal, but I’ll get a haircut tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been tenderly prodding my recollection of that visceral feeling of helplessness, of knowing there was nothing I could do to free myself from this machine. I can’t really help it&amp;mdash;it’s a sore, new wound that I can’t leave alone, located somewhere unknown inside my body. It is a painful warning of how we unavoidably trust systems, and how we must design them accordingly. As things become more automated and more artificially intelligent, this is an intimate reminder of why I care about building safe AI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I touch this emotional memory, I’m also touching a profound sense of my own fragility. Sometimes, there’s literally nothing you can do but try to breathe and stay afloat. I can’t be sure how close I was to dying, but what  matters, and lingers, is the emotional experience of thinking that it is a very near possibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bodily danger feels very different to purely psychological danger. I’m lucky that I don’t feel so breakable on a daily basis; most of us don’t normally shoulder an awareness of being physically, mortally threatened. But at some level, I have to feel grateful to be confronted with an emotional taste of the knowledge that I am&amp;mdash;life is&amp;mdash;that frail. There are things that, as flesh and bone, I just so obviously cannot conquer, even as I go through life believing in my agency. Losing agency is, perhaps, one way to understand what having agency means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Written on Sep 13)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note on Sep 14: If I’ve talked to you about this in the last few days, thank you so much for helping me process it. You are wonderful. Also thanks to Nick Cammarata for suggesting the point about anxiety, ketamine and dissociation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’m not sure about legal action. What I would really like to do is help prevent this experience from happening to anyone again, specifically within a flotation tank but also more broadly, in interactions with any technology. I’ll figure out whether pressing charges gets me there, or if something else does.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Another bit probably worth mentioning: New Zealand has almost no new cases of COVID-19 at the moment, and we are not under lockdown, so you needn&amp;rsquo;t be worried about my virus exposure.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leisure</title>
      <link>https://saffronh.github.io/post/leisure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saffronh.github.io/post/leisure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What is the optimal amount of leisure time and why are Westerners not getting there?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtually Social</title>
      <link>https://saffronh.github.io/post/virtually-social/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saffronh.github.io/post/virtually-social/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“I’m sorry I can’t make section today,” I thumbed into my phone, four minutes before class was due to start. “I had thought it might be difficult to paint outdoors at this time because it’s sunrise here, and the light keeps changing, but on top of that it’s now raining. Can I do the painting later?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The email whizzed off. I made coffee and looked out the window. The droplets were mistier now, and the sun had almost wiped out the baby-pink streaks of dawn with fully-fledged rays. Maybe I could just get through the work now, rather than have the task (&amp;ldquo;Studio Assignment #8: Plein Air Painting&amp;rdquo;) sit on my mind for the next few days. Aurora pinged me back, consenting to my absence from class. I deliberated, gathered my brushes in the name of anti-procrastination and propped a gessoed canvas up in the backyard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ten minutes into tracing the edges of three empty pots in the crusted vegetable garden, I remembered that section was still happening over Zoom. Should I dial in? The inertia of my solitude groaned somewhere inside my body. I thought about the feeling of surveilling and being surveilled by pixellated classmates, and went on mixing paint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After we’d been sent home in the middle of the semester, Matt and Aurora had done their best to keep our painting studio class edifying and enjoyable. Four days into my post-arrival quarantine at home, a large square package reached my door containing four canvases, paper, oil paints, gesso, solvent and extra brushes. I found the receipt in the box, realised how much they’d spent on me, and felt tired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first painting class I’ve taken. Three days after an email notified us to leave campus, I rolled up my splotchy paintings in my suitcase, worrying that this gratifying experiment had met its end. Physically splintering apart could twist this studio class so completely that, even with a personal tub of gesso mailed to my door, it was over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past month, our painting section had morphed from studio time to breakout room discussions of each other&amp;rsquo;s photographed work. This week was actually unusual in that we&amp;rsquo;d attempt to return to live painting, and to evoke the coworking space that we&amp;rsquo;d had before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like having a routine to slide me out of solitude. Walking to class listening to music or coaxing the key out of the door gets me ready for public spaces, for giving and receiving attention. It’s like the feeling of grinding coffee in your pyjamas, the beans nudging your dozing nose awake for another day of breathing. I dread the cold-water shock of joining group calls; the sudden surveillance of a webcam is too rude. The thought of dialing in to section 15 minutes late was too weary to entertain, until guilt took over and I picked up my phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I get a similar feeling whenever I click on the link to attend my English seminar. I love this class, and the way it feels like book club, but it now requires 3:52am alarms (noon in Boston is four in the morning in New Zealand) and focusing my straggling attention on flat little people in flat little boxes on my screen for two-and-a-half hours. I’ll watch my professor explaining some line from &lt;em&gt;Effi Briest&lt;/em&gt;, and imagine trying to figure out if the 23 muted faces, eyes directed somewhere unknowable, understood your take on the merits of Mr. and Mrs. Briest&amp;rsquo;s parenting style. I imagine not getting any feedback from the usual shuffling feet or coughing, and wondering whether the connection might have broken during a critical pedagogical moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now he’s joking about people tuning out, and I anxiously raise my eyebrows at the computer—attentively, I hope—to stem the virtual awkwardness. Look, someone is paying attention to you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not such an eager student in other classes. The first week I had my video on in my quantum lecture. Only one other person did. I committed, stubbornly, to keeping the camera on. The norms for virtual attention were still malleable, I thought, and I didn’t want the professor to feel abandoned by default.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second week, I’d quickly learned that I was not influential enough to change virtual classroom norms, and anyway, the administrators had decided to change the grading status of all classes to a universal pass/fail system. I switched the camera off, rolled out my yoga mat, and spent lecture stretching on the floor. Barely listening, I played a round of minigolf on my phone with a friend, thinking absent-mindedly about how all the difficulties of the game were missing in its digital manifestation — you didn’t have to remind yourself to use the right power, swing your arms just enough, don’t forget to maintain the angle. Everything had lost its physicality recently; minigolf was just another example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I looked up from my screens, I’d become distracted by the immense dimensionality that exists in the physical environment. Reflections in a fork! Puckered leaves on a basil plant! Does anyone else ever think about throwing their laptop into the bushes and running away from a life of pixels?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the class, I unmuted myself. In my best casually-enthusiastic voice I projected &lt;em&gt;Thank you!&lt;/em&gt; into the microphone and left as quickly as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Virtual socializing has its intimacies. I no longer meet people in neutral public settings in which we follow the norms of being a guest in a third space. No more coffee catch-ups during which jazzy café music and indifferent baristas subconsciously prompt us towards a familiar mode of public behaviour. Now, we exclusively show up in our homes, implicitly giving every single person we meet a tour of our most private spaces. I see nice headphones and cats walking across keyboards. They see the titles on my bookshelf and the dramatically green desk my dad bought me in high school. Professors and acquaintances can read my space, deduce that I&amp;rsquo;m messy. My sister bursts in to call me to dinner, even though I texted her that I was on an important call.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Public and private have inverted, and finally melted together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are the new norms we&amp;rsquo;re establishing? How are we behaving now?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was scheduled to participate in some informational visits to various organisations in the Bay Area before COVID-19 really hit. Instead of seeing industry leaders lecturing in their offices, I saw the family photos on their coffee tables. One prominent researcher apologised for the presence of an absurdly massive panda floatie propped behind his shoulder; he was using it to block the sun’s glare through the window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would have been so easy to take a screenshot of him and his inflatable panda with the creepy eyes—that&amp;rsquo;s the thing with digital interactions, you never know which of your footprints others are keeping—but it felt like he was investing in us an unanticipated trust, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to fracture the intimacy of our understanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a specific angle that I never used to see people from — throat-first, upward-tilted. Now I see those tipped, exposed faces all the time from the fixed viewpoint of the webcam. It&amp;rsquo;s accentuated by furrowed brows as people look for the unmute button, blurred cheeks as they hurry through their living room. I never asked for this particular intimacy from others, nor did they ask for mine. It just fell on us circumstantially.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some days I love the limited interactions and the focused, quiet lifestyle I&amp;rsquo;m developing. I don’t have to engage in a social performance if I’d rather curl up in my thoughts. Other days I crave running into a friend at Peets and chatting about an upcoming concert, and I can&amp;rsquo;t quite stomach how different virtual conversations are from those accidental hellos. I plead with my brain to forget about that for a few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often, I can only find out how introverted I&amp;rsquo;m feeling through having that online social interaction I&amp;rsquo;m being indecisive about. When I virtually entered the painting class, I sensed tranquility. No one was speaking. Some people had their microphone &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; their video off. My shoulders loosened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I settled down and scraped burnt umber and ultramarine blue together with a palette knife as my classmates worked quietly, moving across my phone screen. It&amp;rsquo;s funny how a single sun can manifest as late afternoon rays on some pixellated faces and, at the same instant, as a feeble morning glow on others who haven&amp;rsquo;t quite reached that point in the day yet. A cricket chirped somewhere in cyberspace, and I heard it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In retrospect, perhaps I should have known that this class would not exhaust my attention in the same punishing way that others tended to. We were gathered online to work alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I wanted to ask something about lecture,” Emily, another senior, began. Matt gave her the go-ahead. Abstract Expressionism (this was the topic of his most recent lecture) is often the movement that people point to when they talk of the moment that art became pretentious. People don&amp;rsquo;t look at Renaissance paintings and say that, really. What was his response to that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wind rustled through a tree somewhere in San Diego.  Solvent swished in Cambridge. I dabbed at my canvas with a caked paper towel, agreeing with Emily in my head. Matt mused on the question, said she was broadly right about that impression, ahh’d a bit about his opinion, and asked Aurora for hers.  She, too, seemed uncertain. “It’s hard to justify making anything,” she said finally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amidst the ebb and flow of sighs and swishes and occasional questions, I would find inspiration in one sound or another, each pulling me into a new well of thought. I floated in the pools in my head, without feeling the usual obligation to climb out of the water and begin the effort of camouflaging the gap between this and The Normal Class Experience We Should Be Having using attentive-looking smiles and thumbs-up emojis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were hearing, feeling, painting together. A shared experience consolidated in virtual snippets of reality and unexpected abstractions, rather than the physical space of the studio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I unfolded my legs and turned off the microphone and camera on my phone, then went inside to make a snack. As I stared at the closed blinds of the kitchen window, munching on a peanut butter and banana sandwich, birdsong emanated from the phone in my pocket. It sounded like someone was dialing in from a forest. I didn’t check to see who, just contentedly let another reality fill my ears. So many guessing games, so many unknowns — opportunities for speculation hid in every corner of a virtual interaction. Perhaps the birdsong broadcaster was unaware that they had their microphone on, or maybe they knew perfectly well that they’d set off ten different trains of thought (about bluejays or avian migration patterns or something else) chugging around the world. Maybe someone did suspect that I’d abandoned painting in favour of eating in the middle of class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The professor’s keyboard clacked. The cyber cricket crooned, and the birds went on. I stood at the kitchen sink, letting the sounds from other people’s realities fill my own, become my own.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elite Disillusionment</title>
      <link>https://saffronh.github.io/post/elite-disillusionment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 23:56:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saffronh.github.io/post/elite-disillusionment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All manner of people take all manner of issue with elite universities. Chief among the usual qualms is the observation that places like Harvard pump out more &lt;a href=&#34;https://features.thecrimson.com/2019/senior-survey/after-harvard/&#34;&gt;financial analysts and consultants&lt;/a&gt; than &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thecrimson.com/article/2014/11/6/consulting-after-harvard-fm/&#34;&gt;appropriate&lt;/a&gt; for a university that purports to educate the &lt;a href=&#34;https://college.harvard.edu/about/mission-vision-history&#34;&gt;transformative citizen-leaders&lt;/a&gt; of tomorrow. Is this really what all these kids came here to do, and why does the mission seem to fall so short? As I reach the tail end of my time here, I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about the distinct ways I&amp;rsquo;ve seen this environment &amp;ndash; with all its trappings, narratives, and institutions &amp;ndash; shape student paths. Sometimes I joke that Harvard is gaslighting all of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;magnificent-dreams&#34;&gt;magnificent dreams&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You get into Harvard by wanting to change the world, by having pie-in-the-sky ambitions. You don&amp;rsquo;t get in by limiting your goals simply to college admission - or, at least, you render that ulterior aim of yours undetectable. On the whole, it has been my experience that Harvard does manage to admit a lot of amazing, well-intentioned, bright people. But it changes them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People get there, and realise that they&amp;rsquo;re not the best, the smartest, or the most hard-working anymore. So they say, okay, my role is not to change the world. That&amp;rsquo;s the role of him, or her, or them, because they&amp;rsquo;re all smarter and more hard-working than I am. The kid who just patented an invention, the other one who wrote two books, and the countless NGO founders who have collectively raised millions of dollars as teenagers. The &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; innovators, with destiny. Although these are largely illusory narratives and impressions, psychologically, their place in the world shifts. People become much less ambitious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They start to think smaller, safer. &lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not good enough for magnificent dreams. Hell, I can&amp;rsquo;t even get into any clubs.&lt;/em&gt; (Exclusivity is a bit of an issue on this campus.) &lt;em&gt;Anyway, how do I even &amp;lsquo;change the world&amp;rsquo; as I&amp;rsquo;d promised everyone upon entry to this place? I&amp;rsquo;m here now and I need to start fulfilling that mission, but man, people don&amp;rsquo;t talk about the logistics.&lt;/em&gt; The scope of their dreams tighten, from can-do-anything to yikes-I&amp;rsquo;m-not-THAT-exceptional-let&amp;rsquo;s-just-climb-the-ladder-that&amp;rsquo;s-meant-for-me. There &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; that guaranteed, successful thing that still impresses people and satisfies parents, but doesn&amp;rsquo;t change anything of substance. As luck would have it, that&amp;rsquo;s exactly the sort of path that career offices tend to be talented at finding and providing &amp;ndash; the stable and prestigious opportunities at firms willing to pay &lt;a href=&#34;https://perma.cc/CP96-3AVH&#34;&gt;up to $18,000&lt;/a&gt; to recruit at career fairs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first two years, when people asked me what I wanted to do with my education, I&amp;rsquo;d think back to the massive fantasies I&amp;rsquo;d concocted in my bedroom as a 17-year-old in Auckland, and feel a bit silly remembering the vague and grandiose notion of changing the world that had underpinned my aims. I mean, I&amp;rsquo;d had more specific ideas than that, but to tell the truth, the only thing I had real confidence in was that I wanted to &lt;em&gt;really contribute something&lt;/em&gt;. I still did, and do. But having control of your life isn&amp;rsquo;t something that just happens to you; you have to be pro-active about it. And at times when I felt swamped with homework* I&amp;rsquo;d grumble to myself that it felt like Harvard was actively preventing me from figuring out what I really should be doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be hugely helpful if students had more breathing room and headspace, or ways to talk about and normalise these thoughts, and collaborate to make their dreams slightly less vague. Likewise, it would go a long way if career services had more resources on strategic decision-making and calculated risk-taking, or access to mentorship from people in &amp;ldquo;non-traditional&amp;rdquo; pathways. There is a lot of underexplored room for improvement in how we guide our young people, and significant mismatches in the labour market as a result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There seems to be a lot of low-hanging fruit and potential for high ROI for solutions in this area. Career choices are some of the most important decisions people make, yet convention expects them to start narrowing down their path early on with very little information or experience trying things out, to prepare years in advance without knowing what the demand for various jobs or skills might be by the time they graduate, to listen to out-of-date advice, to conduct their first job-search almost exclusively within the narrow scope of the companies that choose to recruit at their school, and to place no emphasis on seriously sitting down to forecast how the future might look in 20-30 years when you&amp;rsquo;re mid-career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;uprooted&#34;&gt;uprooted&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By going to college for four years, you become uprooted from your home and community, and lose significant agency and power to serve a community that you know and are committed to. I personally got very disconnected from New Zealand while away &amp;ndash; I felt like I didn&amp;rsquo;t have my finger on the pulse of the place anymore, didn&amp;rsquo;t know what was happening &amp;ndash; and it&amp;rsquo;s hard to replace that with a new town in a new country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who should you be making a change for, what do you invest in, when you&amp;rsquo;re in an inherently transitory position? It&amp;rsquo;s obviously not impossible to do so, but it&amp;rsquo;s a difficulty that many don&amp;rsquo;t anticipate, especially if you&amp;rsquo;re someone that&amp;rsquo;s interested in sustainable, direct and local impact. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to imagine taking up responsibilities in Cambridge community development or the local council, if you know you&amp;rsquo;re only there 26 weeks a year for four years. Although there are plenty of people who volunteer as tutors, mentors and so on, I think the transience pushes many people to focus on self-development instead (including myself). This is completely fine, as personal growth is obviously important, but constant absorption in the self might be teaching students not to prioritise other-regarding goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;psychological-doors&#34;&gt;psychological doors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elite colleges also actually close doors &amp;ndash; at least, psychologically. You don&amp;rsquo;t see Harvard alumni becoming plumbers, or farmers, or opening a corner store, or doing things that aren&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;worthy&amp;rdquo; of their degree, even if that&amp;rsquo;s what makes them happy. The pressure to prove that the price tag and hard work was &amp;ldquo;worth it&amp;rdquo;, and that you &amp;ldquo;lived up to your potential&amp;rdquo;, is an insidious side effect of attendance that no one talks about. It&amp;rsquo;s another barrier to risk-taking &amp;ndash; even though they have an elite degree, which is ironically one of the best career backup plans one could possibly have. (And yes, I acknowledge that this is a privileged problem; it is still a problem.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find that people back home are often &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; more ambitious about changing their part of the world than people at Harvard. At the end of sophomore year I felt blown away at how many Auckland University kids I knew that were starting companies and social enterprises, creating maker spaces, doing art, running for council &amp;ndash; and nonchalantly inventing their own rules, which is something Harvard kids don&amp;rsquo;t seem to do. It might be that they don&amp;rsquo;t harbour so much mental pressure. It might be that they don&amp;rsquo;t take everything so seriously. It might be that they&amp;rsquo;re not so paralysed by and unaccustomed to the idea of failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The obligatory disclaimer is that I am grateful beyond words for my college education, which has permitted me the most eye-opening and irreplaceable experiences. Nevertheless, I like to think of myself as a realist about the kind of place Harvard is, and the spectrum of effects it has on people. There is much impact to be had in solving some of these problems, and in creating environments for college students in which they are empowered to take the risks they want to (especially if they are very well-placed to take risks), have agency, and can more easily find networks of others wanting to be creative and inspired, to create a mutually-reinforcing spiral of creativeness and inspiration until everyone explodes in a burst of glitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, elite schools open doors, but it&amp;rsquo;s about what you do with your education regardless of where or if you attend college. And (my main point) it&amp;rsquo;s about whether your mind is free from all the new narratives and pressures, finding ways past potential disillusionment and isolation to create connections, to do scary things and to breathe life into the dreams that you seek. I&amp;rsquo;ve found it to be a fulfilling experience, and I&amp;rsquo;m thankful that I currently feel no less ambitious than I did before. It hasn&amp;rsquo;t been an easy or wholly happy ride &amp;ndash; but one that has forced me to figure out what I actually care about (which is continuously a work in progress). If you make sure that you don&amp;rsquo;t lose yourself in the madness, you really can find yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;* As some who know me will have heard me complain, homework comprising 70% of one&amp;rsquo;s semester grade was something entirely new to me at the start of college. I thought that homework was a learning aid, to help you as you went along and started really understanding the material and putting it all together in your head. Unfortunately, it&amp;rsquo;s mostly just a weekly stressor (or in the case of one of my first-year maths classes, 3x a week, each due at 9am) that you have to get basically perfect without fail, if you have any hope of getting an A. Everyone spends all their time nit-picking tricky and specific details rather than ensuring that they have a deep comprehension of the material&amp;hellip; (When you have three problem sets per week, and a host of other things to deal with in your academic/extracurricular/social life, it&amp;rsquo;s funny how myopic your education can become)&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elite Disillusionment (Annotated)</title>
      <link>https://saffronh.github.io/post/elite-disillusionment-annotated/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 02:56:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saffronh.github.io/post/elite-disillusionment-annotated/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;After drafting, I sent this to a few people, including my good friend &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/matthewdsun&#34;&gt;Matt Sun&lt;/a&gt; who made some insightful comments, drawing from his Stanford experience. I love to put pieces in conversation and see what emerges, so asked him to share those comments, which he kindly agreed to do. You are reading the annotated version of this (other version is &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;here&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;). I would be interested in seeing whether others (you?) have thoughts on these topics too. Also, this piece inspired a much longer and much more biting &lt;a href=&#34;https://palladiummag.com/2020/07/27/harvard-creates-managers-instead-of-elites/&#34;&gt;analysis&lt;/a&gt; of elite education I wrote for Palladium Magazine.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All manner of people take all manner of issue with elite universities. Chief among the usual qualms is the observation that places like Harvard pump out more &lt;a href=&#34;https://features.thecrimson.com/2019/senior-survey/after-harvard/&#34;&gt;financial analysts and consultants&lt;/a&gt; than &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thecrimson.com/article/2014/11/6/consulting-after-harvard-fm/&#34;&gt;appropriate&lt;/a&gt; for a university that purports to educate the &lt;a href=&#34;https://college.harvard.edu/about/mission-vision-history&#34;&gt;transformative citizen-leaders&lt;/a&gt; of tomorrow. Is this really what all these kids came here to do, and why does the mission seem to fall so short? As I reach the tail end of my time here, I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about the distinct ways I&amp;rsquo;ve seen this environment &amp;ndash; with all its trappings, narratives, and institutions &amp;ndash; shape student paths. Sometimes I joke that Harvard is gaslighting all of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;magnificent-dreams&#34;&gt;magnificent dreams&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You get into Harvard by wanting to change the world, by having pie-in-the-sky ambitions. You don&amp;rsquo;t get in by limiting your goals simply to college admission - or, at least, you render that ulterior aim of yours undetectable. On the whole, it has been my experience that Harvard does manage to admit a lot of amazing, well-intentioned, bright people. But it changes them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People get there, and &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;realise that they&amp;rsquo;re not the best, the smartest, or the most hard-working anymore.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
So they say, okay, my role is not to change the world. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s the role of him, or her, or them, because they&amp;rsquo;re all smarter and more hard-working than I am.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; The kid who just patented an invention, the other one who wrote two books, and the countless NGO founders who have collectively raised millions of dollars as teenagers. The &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; innovators, with destiny. Although these are largely illusory narratives and impressions, psychologically, their place in the world shifts. People become much less ambitious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They start to think smaller, safer. &lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not good enough for magnificent dreams. Hell, I can&amp;rsquo;t even get into any clubs.&lt;/em&gt; (Exclusivity is a bit of an issue on this campus.) &lt;em&gt;Anyway, how do I even &amp;lsquo;change the world&amp;rsquo; as I&amp;rsquo;d promised everyone upon entry to this place? I&amp;rsquo;m here now and I need to start fulfilling that mission, but man, people don&amp;rsquo;t talk about the logistics.&lt;/em&gt; The scope of their dreams tighten, from can-do-anything to yikes-I&amp;rsquo;m-not-THAT-exceptional-let&amp;rsquo;s-just-climb-the-ladder-that&amp;rsquo;s-meant-for-me. There &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; that guaranteed, successful thing that still impresses people and satisfies parents, but doesn&amp;rsquo;t change anything of substance. As luck would have it, that&amp;rsquo;s exactly the sort of path that career offices tend to be talented at finding and providing &amp;ndash; the stable and prestigious opportunities at firms willing to pay &lt;a href=&#34;https://perma.cc/CP96-3AVH&#34;&gt;up to $18,000&lt;/a&gt; to recruit at career fairs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first two years, when people asked me what I wanted to do with my education, I&amp;rsquo;d think back to the massive fantasies I&amp;rsquo;d concocted in my bedroom as a 17-year-old in Auckland, and feel a bit silly remembering the vague and grandiose notion of changing the world that had underpinned my aims. I mean, I&amp;rsquo;d had more specific ideas than that, but to tell the truth, the only thing I had real confidence in was that I wanted to &lt;em&gt;really contribute something&lt;/em&gt;. I still did, and do. But having control of your life isn&amp;rsquo;t something that just happens to you; you have to be pro-active about it. And at times when I felt swamped with homework* I&amp;rsquo;d grumble to myself that it felt like Harvard was actively preventing me from figuring out what I really should be doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be hugely helpful if students had more breathing room and headspace, or ways to talk about and normalise these thoughts, and collaborate to make their dreams slightly less vague. Likewise, it would go a long way if career services had more resources on strategic decision-making and calculated risk-taking, or access to mentorship from people in &amp;ldquo;non-traditional&amp;rdquo; pathways. There is a lot of underexplored room for improvement in how we guide our young people, and significant mismatches in the labour market as a result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There seems to be a lot of low-hanging fruit and potential for high ROI for solutions in this area. Career choices are some of the most important decisions people make, yet convention expects them to start narrowing down their path early on with very little information or experience trying things out, to prepare years in advance without knowing what the demand for various jobs or skills might be by the time they graduate, to listen to out-of-date advice, to conduct their first job-search almost exclusively within the narrow scope of the companies that choose to recruit at their school, and to place no emphasis on seriously sitting down to forecast how the future might look in 20-30 years when you&amp;rsquo;re mid-career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;uprooted&#34;&gt;uprooted&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By going to college for four years, you become uprooted from your home and community, and lose significant agency and power to serve a community that you know and are committed to. I personally got very disconnected from New Zealand while away &amp;ndash; I felt like I didn&amp;rsquo;t have my finger on the pulse of the place anymore, didn&amp;rsquo;t know what was happening &amp;ndash; and it&amp;rsquo;s hard to replace that with a new town in a new country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who should you be making a change for, what do you invest in, when you&amp;rsquo;re in an inherently transitory position? It&amp;rsquo;s obviously not impossible to do so, but it&amp;rsquo;s a difficulty that many don&amp;rsquo;t anticipate, especially if you&amp;rsquo;re someone that&amp;rsquo;s interested in sustainable, direct and local impact. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to imagine taking up responsibilities in Cambridge community development or the local council, if you know you&amp;rsquo;re only there 26 weeks a year for four years. Although there are plenty of people who volunteer as tutors, mentors and so on, I think the transience pushes many people to focus on self-development instead (including myself). &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;This is completely fine, as personal growth is obviously important, but constant absorption in the self might be teaching students not to prioritise other-regarding goals.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;psychological-doors&#34;&gt;psychological doors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elite colleges also actually close doors &amp;ndash; at least, psychologically. You don&amp;rsquo;t see Harvard alumni becoming plumbers, or farmers, or opening a corner store, or doing things that aren&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;worthy&amp;rdquo; of their degree, even if that&amp;rsquo;s what makes them happy. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;The pressure to prove that the price tag and hard work was &amp;ldquo;worth it&amp;rdquo;, and that you &amp;ldquo;lived up to your potential&amp;rdquo;, is an insidious side effect of attendance that no one talks about.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s another barrier to risk-taking &amp;ndash; even though they have an elite degree, which is ironically one of the best career backup plans one could possibly have. (And yes, I acknowledge that this is a privileged problem; it is still a problem.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find that people back home are often &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; more ambitious about changing their part of the world than people at Harvard. At the end of sophomore year I felt blown away at how many Auckland University kids I knew that were starting companies and social enterprises, creating maker spaces, doing art, running for council &amp;ndash; and nonchalantly inventing their own rules, which is something Harvard kids don&amp;rsquo;t seem to do. It might be that they don&amp;rsquo;t harbour so much mental pressure. It might be that they don&amp;rsquo;t take everything so seriously. It might be that they&amp;rsquo;re not so paralysed by and unaccustomed to the idea of failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The obligatory disclaimer is that I am grateful beyond words for my college education, which has permitted me the most eye-opening and irreplaceable experiences. Nevertheless, I like to think of myself as a realist about the kind of place Harvard is, and the spectrum of effects it has on people. There is much impact to be had in solving some of these problems, and in creating environments for college students in which they are empowered to take the risks they want to (especially if they are very well-placed to take risks), have agency, and can more easily find networks of others wanting to be creative and inspired, to create a mutually-reinforcing spiral of creativeness and inspiration until everyone explodes in a burst of glitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, elite schools open doors, but it&amp;rsquo;s about what you do with your education regardless of where or if you attend college. And (my main point) it&amp;rsquo;s about whether your mind is free from all the new narratives and pressures, finding ways past potential disillusionment and isolation to create connections, to do scary things and to breathe life into the dreams that you seek. I&amp;rsquo;ve found it to be a fulfilling experience, and I&amp;rsquo;m thankful that I currently feel no less ambitious than I did before. It hasn&amp;rsquo;t been an easy or wholly happy ride &amp;ndash; but one that has forced me to figure out what I actually care about (which is continuously a work in progress). If you make sure that you don&amp;rsquo;t lose yourself in the madness, you really can find yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;* As some who know me will have heard me complain, homework comprising 70% of one&amp;rsquo;s semester grade was something entirely new to me at the start of college. I thought that homework was a learning aid, to help you as you went along and started really understanding the material and putting it all together in your head. Unfortunately, it&amp;rsquo;s mostly just a weekly stressor (or in the case of one of my first-year maths classes, 3x a week, each due at 9am) that you have to get basically perfect without fail, if you have any hope of getting an A. Everyone spends all their time nit-picking tricky and specific details rather than ensuring that they have a deep comprehension of the material&amp;hellip; (When you have three problem sets per week, and a host of other things to deal with in your academic/extracurricular/social life, it&amp;rsquo;s funny how myopic your education can become)&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent Mental Shifts</title>
      <link>https://saffronh.github.io/post/recent-mental-shifts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 14:56:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saffronh.github.io/post/recent-mental-shifts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been enjoying the freshness of arrival in London, of beginning to piece together a routine, of new friends and conversations, and of more time for thought. Some things I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I need to use my public voice more (i.e. put content online). There are a few reasons for this: Firstly, the best people are also the most prolific; you don&amp;rsquo;t improve by waiting months or years between releasing creations you deem perfect enough to see the light of day. Iteration is necessary to improvement, so get it out there. Secondly, my thoughts are actually&amp;hellip; not even that bad. Sometimes they&amp;rsquo;re even good. In any case, they could be useful to people (or eventually useful&amp;ndash;publicity allows for feedback which allows for improvement; see previous point). Thirdly, it makes me think more rigorously about the claims I make, and whether I&amp;rsquo;m willing to defend them in public. Fourthly, letting fears (in this case, of personal judgment) dictate my actions is both emotionally and logically bad, and I&amp;rsquo;m trying to get over unnecessarily scary things in general. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;em&gt;01/12 Update: Using platforms like Twitter, where people can easily respond/connect, makes this much better - real humans are out there, not just judgy anons!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The narratives I tell myself about myself are all-important and very malleable. (I knew this intellectually, but rarely hacked this to change my actions.)&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Goal-setting is a recent example. I&amp;rsquo;ve historically struggled with motivating myself to follow through on my set goals, because I found it hard to be sufficiently motivated by focusing mostly on the ends. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure this came from a lack of ability to granularize my goals into little, quantifiable ones - even when I did, the motivation to carry me through the smaller milestones was low. I think this is because my self-narrative implicitly stressed the gap between my current self and who I wanted to be, making the rift loom large enough that I felt dispirited. (Perfectionism definitely contributed to this, too.) But if I simply tell myself that &lt;em&gt;that&amp;rsquo;s the kind of person I am&lt;/em&gt;, and try to autopilot my way through my small goals as if I&amp;rsquo;ve done so all my life, I&amp;rsquo;ve found that I just carry through. So, rather than &amp;lsquo;I need to strive towards this destination&amp;rsquo;, instead thinking &amp;lsquo;I&amp;rsquo;m the kind of person who likes to do the steps along the way&amp;rsquo;. (&lt;strong&gt;More succinctly, &amp;lsquo;what do I like to do?&amp;rsquo;, instead of &amp;lsquo;who do I want to be?&#39;&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I function best when I have one main priority, and the time to focus on it. School is often difficult and stressful, not because it&amp;rsquo;s a lot of hours of work, but because of the mental management of diverse and conflicting priorities, and lack of agency (having to do things I don&amp;rsquo;t think are that important). Focusing on 1-2 objectives at work, and having auxiiliary hobbies that I enjoy (like actually having time for reading!), makes me so much happier, even if I&amp;rsquo;m just as occupied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frequently interacting with, working with, and befriending people of different ages is so beneficial, and constantly checks your perspective. My colleagues are all at &lt;em&gt;least&lt;/em&gt; 5 years older than me (I&amp;rsquo;d guess that most of them are in their 30s? I&amp;rsquo;m bad with estimating ages? Help?), and I&amp;rsquo;m living with people in their late 20s-early 30s. I think it&amp;rsquo;s implicitly helped me prioritize longer-term projects and aims, rather than short-term urgencies (which are generally less important, see 3) above) and provided me a more cohesive picture of what I could be at different stages of life to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been using &lt;strong&gt;scale&lt;/strong&gt; as a mental model a lot recently. Scale is perhaps the most important factor to consider when looking into the past/future and analyzing how things change. It also creates massive problems and opportunities. It&amp;rsquo;s very useful to think: how does this thing change when you multiply it by 10x, or 1000x? how do the characteristics of this (costs, benefits, other qualities) change if only one individual were acting this way, vs. a city of people all doing so, vs. the entire world?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burn</title>
      <link>https://saffronh.github.io/post/burn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2019 02:56:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saffronh.github.io/post/burn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve never previously said or believed that any single experience has changed me. Sure, I can point to things that have changed my life, but none of them have necessarily impacted who I &lt;em&gt;am&lt;/em&gt; — they just altered the course of my lived experiences. Reasons for this include: few things actually change a person significantly, it’s often impossible to know whether an experience changes you immediately afterwards, and there’s no alternate reality to let you test whether that’s the case. Despite all this, I am certain that my first Burn changed me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m aware of how absurd and probably &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8e1OEqrdIxY&#34;&gt;obnoxious&lt;/a&gt; this sounds. It&amp;rsquo;s actually pretty hard to publicise this because I don&amp;rsquo;t want to be That Person Who Went to Burning Man, but I do want to share my thoughts with friends in case I can encourage people to experience it for themselves. Another reason this piece exists is that it&amp;rsquo;s just difficult to convey and do justice to this experience in conversation, because it&amp;rsquo;s such a bizarre, ridiculous and hilarious place. I want to write and refine this personal essay in order to process the week, and to ensure that there&amp;rsquo;s at least one place where I&amp;rsquo;m articulating my thoughts in an accurate and considered manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To provide some structure to this essay, I’ll give an overview of what this crazy social experiment is, and then dive into my key learnings and experiences from Burning Man 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;table-of-contents&#34;&gt;Table of contents&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#a-magical-place&#34;&gt;A magical place&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#letting-go&#34;&gt;Letting go and sacrifice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#numbness&#34;&gt;The opposite of numbness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#kindness&#34;&gt;Kindness and care&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#hilarity&#34;&gt;Hilarity and weirdness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#freedom&#34;&gt;Freedom and exploration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#conclusion&#34;&gt;In short&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#more&#34;&gt;More things, goals, etc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-magical-place&#34;&gt;A magical place&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Burning Man happens every year in late August, at Black Rock City (BRC), Nevada — a temporary city constructed on an ancient dried-up lakebed that we call the “playa”. It’s full of camps, art (including some of the largest &lt;a href=&#34;https://burningman.org/event/brc/2019-art-installations/&#34;&gt;art pieces&lt;/a&gt; you’ll ever see and interact with), events, and people that come from all over the world. The 10 principles that reflect the ethos and culture of Burning Man are as follows: radical inclusion, gifting, decommodification, radical self-reliance, radical self-expression, communal effort, civic responsibility, leaving no trace, participation and immediacy. You can read about them &lt;a href=&#34;https://burningman.org/culture/philosophical-center/10-principles/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are around 70,000 people, 2000 camps, and miles upon miles of dusty playa. There’s two main parts of BRC: the “city”, where people camp, and the “deep playa”, where colossal art installations live. People on bikes and in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TyJkFlSYzDU&#34;&gt;mutant vehicles (art cars)&lt;/a&gt; coast through every part of the playa. Many people stay with theme camps, which provide some kind of gift to BRC, although it’s very much possible to camp by yourself or with a group of friends. Camps sport hilarious names from “Ancient Cult of the Alligator” to “Best Butt” and “Kegel Kommandos”, and put on countless events. Camps will serve food and/or drinks, throw incredible parties, organise activities for everyone, activities for kids or activities that are &lt;em&gt;definitely&lt;/em&gt; not for kids, teach workshops, put on talks or performances, or offer support services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;You can do anything in the city.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; You can enjoy a traditional Vietnamese coffee, dance to Tycho’s sunrise set, get lathered, scrubbed and rubbed all over by 10 people in a human car wash, get your hair braided, grab a margarita (one camp mixes their margs using chainsaws), be served champagne by people in silk robes while listening to house music, fight a friend in the Thunder Dome by being swung towards each other in harnesses and beating the shit out of each other with padded bats, watch a movie at the sunset drive-in theatre, climb a geodesic dome and sit in hammocks at the top, stay up all night and watch the sunrise blossom over the mountains, dance on top of the Slutgarden stage, play mini-golf, attend an “Awkward Songs to Strip To” event where everyone is encouraged to strip to the tune of The Wheels on the Bus, bake your own cake, get spanked for a pickle, eat French pastries made by pastry chefs, sing to a crowd, watch professional roller derbyists and fire dancers perform, and more. There’s so much to learn, through countless workshops on aerial arts, contact improv, authentic relating, improving your body image, acroyoga, spanking, massage, tantric breathing, “pirate yoga”, basics of IP law, bookmaking, naked Greek pottery… the list goes on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can walk around nude. You can pop into a random camp and strike up a conversation. You can hitch a lift on an art car (perhaps the one that looks like a pirate ship, or the one that’s essentially just papier-mâché boobs, or the fire-breathing octopus), and ride around people-watching, listening to music, dancing or talking. You can bike through the streets letting serendipity find you, or out into the deep playa to look at and maybe climb some art. You’d head back to your camp to do a volunteer shift, baby-wipe some grime off yourself (although you really just have to resign yourself to a week of being coated in a mixture of dust, sweat and sunscreen), or grab your LED lights to go out at night-time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And all of this is brought to life as gifts from fellow burners to fellow burners. No money exists on the playa, and gifts are not meant to entail reciprocation. They are simply to be enjoyed and appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;letting-go&#34;&gt;Letting go and sacrifice&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I arrived on Monday by myself; my best friend Amanda had driven up on Saturday. That evening, our camp (Dead Hand Path, which had events focused on rationality, spirituality, the occult and science) held an opening ceremony in our &amp;ldquo;Gospel Tent&amp;rdquo;. After each introducing ourselves, we set intentions for the week. I thought for about a minute and then declared that my intention was to let go. More specifically, to let go of expectations, judgments and preconceived notions, and just experience things as close to the surface of reality as possible. I also wanted to let go of my own protectiveness over myself, allowing myself to be vulnerable and trust in other people. This letting-go thing ended up being much more important than I initially realised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I started letting go and going with the flow, everything felt serendipitous and magical. (Granted, burners are really good at making little things feel like magic, as Amanda put it). Just when my lights ran out of battery, I came across a box of LEDs. Just when Amanda and I needed to drag our suitcases across the dust to load into a friend&amp;rsquo;s car, someone pulled up on a golf cart and started chatting to us, and ended up giving us a ride over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only is letting go crucial to enjoying all the other elements of Burning Man that I&amp;rsquo;m writing way too much about in this post, it also really helped me deal with negative emotions and situations that arose. During a walk with Amanda after a particularly emotionally taxing event, we stumbled upon a booth sporting a sign reading “Got anything you need to let go of?” Well, actually yes we did. A guy was chilling on the cushions next to the sign. We sat down next to him and explained our predicament, after which he gave us each a necklace with a “Let it Go” pendant. “The necklace is just passing through you,” he explained. “When the moment feels right, give it to the next person who needs to let something go.” (Woah, a Let it Go necklace that’s made to be let go of! *mind explodes*) Such symbolic tokens became important reminders of the mindset I wanted to carry throughout the week, and honestly I initially didn’t want to give it away. But when I eventually passed the necklace along to someone else in a difficult situation, I realised that doing so felt just right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Letting things go is also about sacrifice. The intent of the necklace is a small example of a community that is incredibly willing to sacrifice things that they love for others. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;At the Shots for Shocks bar, Amanda and I got our buttcheeks shocked by a cattle prod&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; in exchange for some deliciously infused liqueur. (It felt like a bee punching me, if you were wondering.) After downing our shots, we started chatting to the bartender about the history of the land and burner culture. She told us about some of her longtime burner friends who come year after year, and eventually end up spending almost all of their time volunteering, such that virgin burners like me can safely have the time of their lives. She herself had decided to split her entire week between this bar and the Temple, where she worked shifts as a Temple Guardian. It’s hard for me to imagine spending so much time and money coming to Burning Man, the ultimate candy-shop wonderland of humanity, and prioritising other people’s wellbeing and time above my own. But as I witnessed countless people exemplifying this over the course of the week, I began to understand how much joy is created from interacting with others in this way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems that all of Burning Man is building shit for others and destroying it thoughtfully, out of love. The entire metropolis is built from scratch by participants every year, coming alive for a week before being disassembled. We carefully comb the playa to remove matter-out-of-place (MOOP) i.e. anything that&amp;rsquo;s not dust, and crews are employed for months afterwards to restore the earth. The big art installations are often made of wood, and near the end of the week many get set on fire one by one, and literally burned to the ground. Flying blazing debris, dust vortexes and all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to imagine how much time, energy, love and engineering chops were put into something like The Folly — the massive building made of reclaimed lumber ablaze in the video, sporting a clock tower and windmill. Three days before I’d watched a full-scale orchestra perform a two-hour concert in its shade, and now everything was falling into the dust. The artists and builders do really &lt;a href=&#34;https://mixmag.net/feature/burning-man-the-folly&#34;&gt;represent the soul of Black Rock City&lt;/a&gt;. I can only imagine the strength of will and resilience that is requisite for letting go of the structure that they&amp;rsquo;d poured a year of work into. Or maybe, it&amp;rsquo;s a cathartic feeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next evening I watched the Man itself burn, complete with a breathtaking fireworks show and troupes of fire dancers. As the top of the structure caved in, it became clear that destruction is okay, and even beautiful. Especially when you&amp;rsquo;re destroying things for the benefit of others—this particular show is collecting tens of thousands of people, and bringing us all a sense of wonder—and when the sacrifice is painful, beauty emerges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/wnVvtET.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;catharsis&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
                    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/B15gA2zg0SW/&#34;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/nKfYUOc.gif&#34;
         alt=&#34;from space&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
                    &lt;a href=&#34;https://time.com/5663633/burning-man-festival-space/&#34;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;numbness&#34;&gt;The opposite of numbness&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the week, our camp had its closing ceremony — our own mini burn. When it came to my turn, I wrote &amp;ldquo;numbness&amp;rdquo; on my piece of wood and threw it into the fire, willing it to go up in flames. The week had been a chance to sit with feelings and sensations that I normally dismiss and/or quickly move on from. This allowed me insights, joy and relief that the usual numbness doesn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; I experienced being awakened, affected and stimulated in entirely new ways.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; I took a contact improv dance class, forging a sense of closeness and intimacy with my fellow dancers — the kind that is possible only through touching and experiencing each other&amp;rsquo;s bodies (in non-sexual ways). I listened to music so beautiful it brought me to tears, felt the kind of deep empathy with another person that changes your worldview, and experienced art that left my jaw on the floor. Intimate conversations became  easy and natural, and strangers quickly felt like close friends. I&amp;rsquo;m not a touchy-feely person in the default world, but I let myself fully sink into deep, lingering hugs, and got so much better at maintaining eye contact. Hell, even being &lt;a href=&#34;#cattle&#34;&gt;cattle-prodded&lt;/a&gt; counts as a new stimulus that I opened myself and my buttcheeks up to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emotionally and physically, I let myself become closer to others. At one workshop, I met Brian, the man with deep-set eyes and warm smile who constantly sought to lift others up with his words, but admitted how hard it was to let himself believe anything kind that others said about him. I met Roxy who wore a poofy yellow dress stitched with butterflies, her blue eyes welling up as she thought back to the last time she felt truly loved. Most burners, including them, were older than me, but that didn&amp;rsquo;t really seem to matter to friendship and connection on the playa. No one that I personally knew had ever gave me a foot massage before Burning Man - I reserved this intimacy exclusively for paid strangers. The thought of someone I knew kneading my calves would send me into a panic along the lines of &amp;ldquo;oh god that is so intimate oh god get away.&amp;rdquo; But when my campmate Michael offered to loosen up the knots in my bike-worn feet, I happily obliged. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t even avoiding eye contact!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My brain likes to put up resistance to experiences of intimacy, because I&amp;rsquo;m a really self-sufficient person who is afraid of dependence. Pushing past that fear, I encountered an abundance of non-sexual intimacy that week, which unexpectedly led to (surprise!) understanding and empathy, rather than the emotional reliance on others that I arbitrarily fear. (Of course, there is also sexual intimacy at Burning Man, but in my opinion, non-sexual intimacy is more rare in the default world so it&amp;rsquo;s more interesting to experience and discuss.) Turns out, feeling things is an asset; it allows you to access insights that rational thought doesn&amp;rsquo;t lead to (or would at least require many circuitous leaps to arrive at).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;kindness&#34;&gt;Kindness and care&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gifting is one of the core principles of Burning Man. One doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to do anything to deserve a gift, and this ethos steeps the playa in kindness and joy. At any given minute I&amp;rsquo;d be offered Thai iced tea, dust goggles or face painting. At the Man burn, someone offered our group fuzzy handmade hats, and two minutes later another person brought over lollipops. I felt very taken care of and connected to others. I also had some of the most empathetic experiences of my life, and I hope to contribute more when I come back next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Non-human things are also painstakingly cared for. The Leave No Trace ethos exemplifies this; at the end of the week, lines of people form all over the playa, carefully inspecting the raked dust for any trash. It often feels like the playa is out to kill me, and it left my face disgustingly dry and flaky. Still, we should take care of the earth and leave it as we found it, even when it&amp;rsquo;s not always good to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;hilarity&#34;&gt;Hilarity and weirdness&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the weirdest shit of my life so far happened at Burning Man. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure where else I could get spoon-fed a five-course meal, freely climb 25 ft towers, spank (and be spanked by) a stranger, spend too long staring at a giant psychedelic snail mutant vehicle, hang out with a bunch of conspiracy theorists, participate in an ecstatic dance session at a Mexican billionaire&amp;rsquo;s camp, or stand bafflingly close to a blazing building trying to dodge flaming embers. One quick glance at the camp names, or a list of &lt;a href=&#34;#events&#34;&gt;events&lt;/a&gt;, and it&amp;rsquo;s obvious that weirdness - and the joy that comes with it - is openly embraced in Black Rock City.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also realised that &lt;em&gt;so many of these things are made to fuck with you&lt;/em&gt;. So many things are meant to make you double-take, rethink your initial judgments, crack up laughing. Putting in so much work just to mess with people - that&amp;rsquo;s incredible and I love it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;freedom&#34;&gt;Freedom and exploration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The open embrace of hilarity and weirdness and the lack of judgment led to a feeling of liberation that I&amp;rsquo;ve scarcely felt before. &amp;ldquo;Choose your own adventure&amp;rdquo; became a motto. It&amp;rsquo;s like when you&amp;rsquo;re travelling abroad and you don&amp;rsquo;t know anyone, so there are no consequences for exploring new things - except you can come back year after year to the playa, get to know more people, and they still won&amp;rsquo;t judge you. It&amp;rsquo;s not like I became a completely different person; it&amp;rsquo;s more that I felt comfortable embodying an extremely authentic version of myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t personally walk around naked. But what I realised after one person I found intimidating walked around camp topless one day, was that we&amp;rsquo;re all fleshy humans with weird bits. Intellectually I know this, but there&amp;rsquo;s something about standing there talking to someone with not much fabric between us, that makes me appreciate how similar we all are in our materiality, insecurities and vulnerabilities. Casual nudity is honestly just cool. It adds to the open, comfortable, nonjudgmental and safe environment, which &lt;a href=&#34;#awakened&#34;&gt;removes&lt;/a&gt; unnecessary barriers to &lt;a href=&#34;#events&#34;&gt;exploration&lt;/a&gt; that exist in the default world. At first I didn&amp;rsquo;t understand why BDSM and sex camps are so plentiful at Burning Man. Well, how do people actually learn these things in the default world, except through getting messed-up ideas from porn? Turns out, this is a rare opportunity to find experts who are willing to show people the ropes and talk through awkward topics in a safe and easily-accessible environment, free of charge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;In short&amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day after I got back, I felt roused from a dream. As iPhone notifications started pinging, and it became socially inappropriate to wrap people in full-body hugs, I began missing that alternate reality a whole lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a week of letting down barriers and interacting with people in refreshingly non-standard ways, but it was just a week. I have a lot still to learn about letting go and learning to make sacrifices that are actually difficult, and about becoming the kind of person that brings a touch of joy, laughter and magic to others&#39; experiences. I have a lot to learn about channeling empathy. And of course, it&amp;rsquo;s only really useful if I&amp;rsquo;m doing this in the default world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m convinced that the full range of human emotions and experiences exist at Burning Man, as well as some of the most beautiful creations of man and earth. I do think that you have to be somewhat open-minded to tap into this, because the place is absurdity incarnate. (If you&amp;rsquo;re still reading this and interested, you probably are.) And of course, it&amp;rsquo;s also all about who you experience it with &amp;ndash; Amanda and I were very comfortable with each other beforehand, yet it&amp;rsquo;s safe to say we got even closer. Friends who _____ together stay together (fill in the blank with any of our bizarre mishaps).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I developed a heightened appreciation of art. Some of the most difficult-to-describe experiences I&amp;rsquo;ve ever had occurred that week, and though I&amp;rsquo;m trying to put pen to paper, it feels like the only things that really reflect those feelings are the art on the playa. Knowing the astounding amounts of love, work and care poured into these pieces makes them even more incredible (I discovered this for myself when I volunteered a day to help take apart pianos for &lt;a href=&#34;https://fundrazr.com/ShrineofSympatheticResonance?ref=ab_8QsPHGszXSk8QsPHGszXSk&#34;&gt;one of them&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s funny, because a lot of the media coverage of Burning Man emphasises degeneracy. In that context, my effusiveness might seem strange. Honestly, I think that Black Rock City is simultaneously the most wholesome and the most degenerate place possible. This really is a choose-your-own adventure. At one point in the week, I watched a jazz soloist perform a song about Burning Man, belting &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s the most fucked up place you&amp;rsquo;ll ever love!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;more&#34;&gt;More things, goals, etc&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An apt &lt;a href=&#34;https://mixmag.net/feature/meet-the-sound-camps-of-burning-man&#34;&gt;description&lt;/a&gt; of Burning Man:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Ancestor” dust storms twist and helix across spanning horizons while soul rapturing sunsets distinguish the apocalyptic lakebed that becomes Black Rock City, the home of the annual Burning Man. The widely celebrated ‘social experiment’ in the desert where spectating is not allowed is called ‘home’ by artists and creators from all over the world. It’s here survivalists, thrill-seekers and a few of Silicon Valley’s elite converge to greet each other in tutus, bandanas and rhinestone emblazoned captains hats, while fire belching mutant vehicles ferry from one camp to the next with a full-fledged dance party in tow. Taken as a whole, the city is equal parts culture, community and art, with plenty of rabbit holes to stumble into. Whether you came for the colossal sculptures, the rich community or the experience of a lifetime there’s something for everyone here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;next-time&#34;&gt;Next time:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pop into camps more often, and strike up random conversations more often.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try to feel a little less self-conscious. (I wasn&amp;rsquo;t exactly used to telling people that I was going to check out a spanking workshop, even if people are &lt;a href=&#34;#freedom&#34;&gt;high-openness&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spend more time making people feel welcome and at-home.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;things-i-want-to-bring-into-my-everyday-life&#34;&gt;Things I want to bring into my everyday life:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make eye contact more often.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make people feel seen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Withhold judgment about other people, and about myself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remember that everything is just set and setting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/nsMHZWT.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;Aerial view of Man burn - unknown source&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Aerial view of Man burn - unknown source&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>contact</title>
      <link>https://saffronh.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2019 01:24:07 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saffronh.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Please feel free to reach out on &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/saffronhuang&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Title</title>
      <link>https://saffronh.github.io/post/title/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saffronh.github.io/post/title/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Art</title>
      <link>https://saffronh.github.io/post/creating-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 23:56:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saffronh.github.io/post/creating-art/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;written-during-my-summer-internship-in-berlin&#34;&gt;Written during my summer internship in Berlin.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every day I come home to my shared apartment in Prenzlauer Berg, I enter the living room to see Fabian on the balcony, grasping a hand-rolled cigarette and staring into the secluded courtyard that hides behind our apartment block.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll make dinner. Sometimes I’ll put in actual effort and sautée some sad-looking vegetable; other times I’ll eat a mixture of white rice and peanut butter with a spoon. He’ll still be there, soft jazzy beats bouncing from his cream-coloured Marshall amplifier. I’ll clean up, attempting to make the kitchen pristine enough to be photographed for sale tomorrow (an impressive ability to stay spotless and tidy on Ana and Fabian’s behalf). He’ll still be there, languidly inspecting his array of young bamboos and herbs, amongst which shoots of fake greenery have been placed to cover the gaps where gardening attempts went awry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I often wonder what he’s thinking about. I wonder how he can stay there for hours, appearing to doing nothing but chain-smoke. Does he ever feel unproductive? I wonder at what kind of contrast is occurring between the exterior and the interior. Maybe, since he is a psychiatrist on weekdays, he’s reflecting on what he’s seen at work, calming his mind. This nightly ritual could be a period of general reflection — perhaps on work, yes, but also life, family, relationships, politics. I have never asked him about it, though, and every time I come in from work he smiles and directs the focus onto me, “Wie war den Tag?” I feel as if I’ve wandered into his world and clumsily broken something every time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I came home to see pink graffiti scrawled on the glass balcony doors. Excess drips of neon paint meandered down the glass, through which I could see Fabian lounging on the balcony beside the cigarette papers and tobacco piles at the ready. This sudden “vandalism” gave the normally minimalist, white (and slightly sterile) aesthetic of the apartment a cheekiness that I never thought possible. “Did you do this?” I asked him, not wanting to make an incorrect assumption (perhaps its artist was Ana) since clearly, this occurence showed that my assumptions about others are so often wrong. Not &lt;em&gt;wrong&lt;/em&gt;, but wrong in the sense that they’re not generous enough to allow space to conceive them as creative beings with imaginations and impulses. I unconsciously categorize people too much; if they display their drawings and paintings on social media then they’re An Artist; I imagine that inexplicable Artistic Wheels are constantly spinning in their head, somehow churning out pretty visualisations that they translate through paints or 2B pencils or tablets. For Normal People, I become unreasonably surprised at seeing them exhibit the creativity that is really within us all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thursday was Ascension Day, a public holiday. I decided to take the U-Bahn to see The Haus, an exhibition on Nürnberger Straße. The TL;DR of the exhibit is: 160 artists locked into a 5-storey building, each artist gets to do whatever with their own room, building is destroyed on June 1st. I ended up waiting 4.5 (!!!) hours on a cold and windy spring day to see it. But I didn’t mind; the people in line in front of me jumped and danced for warmth with me, shared their mini Lindt pralines and strawberries with me, shouted me coffee, held my spot in line when I bought a chai latte to reverse the blue-ification of my lips, and talked to me about Berlin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most memorably, they pulled out miscellaneous sketchbooks and a roll of pencils of varying intensities, and sat in line sketching (former) strangers whilst conversing in German and laughing away the hours. First, the girl behind us with a nose ring, bright fabric headband and discerning blue eyes that looked on intently as they drew. Second, the man in front of us with a pink shirt, dark rectangular glasses and a closely-cropped head of silvering hair who seemed amused at the proceedings. I marvelled at how well one of them, a tall young man with dreadlocks and tortoiseshell glasses, drew and expressed that I wished I drew that well. He immediately responded, “You want to try?” and passed me a notebook and pencil. My pink-shirt-guy portrait wasn’t fantastic, and I hurried to make it bear some sort of resemblance as everyone else had almost finished theirs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A young couple in line with us were also bestowed simple drawing supplies, and we all happily drew on, sharing our works with lighthearted mmms and ahhhs. I’d assumed that the original group would all be fantastic artists, given their enthusiasm for sketching random people. A usual mindset of striving upwards, of always evaluating others and being evaluated for quality, modifies many things into a depersonalised show of skill — &lt;em&gt;like, are you &lt;strong&gt;good&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/em&gt; Again, I was unreasonably surprised that their works weren’t objectively spectacular. And so what? Art is for all to create. Berlin has taught me this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I saw his work, I asked of Fabian what “KEAM 1997” (two parts of the graffiti that I could actually discern) meant. He told me that he’d started painting graffiti as “KEAM” in 1997 — when he was 13. I thought of little 13-year-old Fabian picking up a spray can and laughed, “That’s the year I was born!” Perhaps a dumb little coincidence, but I thought of it it as a signal telling me, I should give it a go. He gave me the pink paint pen and taught me how to press so that liquid oozes and drips out as I mark out my design, and left me to my whims. I drew Pucci (their snowy, prickly-natured cat) and attempted some graffiti lettering. That was it. Nothing special happened before or after, I just picked up the pen and did it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Art-making is so easy and so &lt;em&gt;fun&lt;/em&gt;, but I attach such daunting significance to it, tying it to self-worth and significance and judgment. I assume that Artists possess inherent qualities of interestingness, mysteriousness and creativeness unable to be accessed or contemplated by Normal People such as myself. (I for some reason don&amp;rsquo;t seem to regard my own photography as Art.) Excessively esteeming people who create art elevates them into ideals and away from reality, and fabricates a personality divide where there isn’t one. The irony is that it is achingly simple to make art once you just stop contemplating it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could see Hugo looking at me intently. The bulky bandage gave him an enormous head. ‘The trouble with you, Jake,’ said Hugo, ‘is that you’re far too impressed by people. You were far too impressed by me.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was surprised. ‘I was impressed,’ I said, ‘but I didn’t know you knew.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘Everyone must go his own way, Jake,’ said Hugo. ‘Things don’t matter as much as you think.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Iris Murdoch, Under The Net.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five Weeks In</title>
      <link>https://saffronh.github.io/post/five-weeks-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 23:56:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saffronh.github.io/post/five-weeks-in/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;written-halfway-through-my-summer-internship-in-berlin&#34;&gt;Written halfway through my summer internship in Berlin.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a shock, but at this point I’m more than halfway through my internship. Soon, I&amp;rsquo;ll have to start dismantling the fledgling routine I’ve only just started to establish for myself — getting up, eating, biking to work, trying to stop sweating before I step into the lobby, working, then repeating the whole thing in reverse. I’ll have to sell my purple secondhand bike back to the shop, mail  excess belongings home (neither pair of heels have been touched), and buy a backpack for the next leg of my European travels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What have I done so far? I’ve had incredible beer. I’ve frequently gotten lost on my bike, both accidentally and deliberately. I’ve attended countless fitness classes that I got through not by successfully understanding the instructor&amp;rsquo;s rapid-fire Deutsch, but through a strategy that I like to call quick,-mimick-that-girl&amp;rsquo;s-asana. I’ve bopped in clubs to wordless music, dressed head-to-toe in black.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Dresden I hiked, picnicked, and spent too long in the Hygiene Museum. In Copenhagen I walked 30km each day through the narrow streets and squeezed into a three-tier hostel bunk bed each night. I was led through sketchy bushes and old shipping crates as part of a photography festival, one which has inspired me to put &amp;ldquo;make ethnographic films&amp;rdquo; on my to-do list. I also saw a morbid but hilariously crude ballet performance about death. In Salzburg I escaped Salzburg and hiked through Berchtesgaden instead. I’ve been approached by more strangers than ever before, and I’ve worked up the nerve to talk to more strangers than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below are some photos from various stints in various places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Woman on a bench outside the Kunstquartier Bethanien.
I take a lot of pictures of strangers, and maybe that makes me a freak. But I find people are so much more interesting than landmarks or buildings. I always notice if a lady is wearing a bright yellow hat or is eating ice cream on a grotty park bench or whatever, and I always find it absurdly photographable. Idk guys, people are beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two Views of Salzburg.
At the entrance to the Mirabell Gardens I took the first picture, turned 180 degrees around and took the second picture. It’s always funny how people flock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deceptive Photo of The Most Touristy Street in Salzburg.
I like to play a game called Can I Make It Look Like I’m The Only Tourist Here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copenhagen Child.
God, I am so weird.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the best brunch buffet I have ever been to. There was such a variety of food: salads, cake and brownie slices, vegan scrambled eggs, amazing quiches, chili, deliciously crispy mini pancakes and hot compote, strawberry polenta, orange/vanilla-lavender chia pudding, yoghurts, little glass jars of thick mousses, various dips, warm bread rolls and pretzels, vegan charcuterie and cheeses. Wow, I died. I&amp;rsquo;m really not the kind of person that starves themselves to go to a buffet and binges on twenty plates, so I was pretty surprised at myself when I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but keep eating and trying EVERYTHING. It was all so fresh and perfectly seasoned and tasty. I went through seven plates&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Service was great, too. Sure, initially I had to wait a while to get a table because the girl seating guests was on the phone having a slow conversation and wouldn&amp;rsquo;t look me in the eye, which was rude, but the waiter that I ended up getting was incredibly polite, friendly, and whisked my plates away regularly so that I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to st&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Absent Conclusions</title>
      <link>https://saffronh.github.io/post/absent-conclusions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2017 23:56:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saffronh.github.io/post/absent-conclusions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-reflection-after-harvard-college-israel-trek-a-spring-break-trip-i-was-fortunate-enough-to-attend&#34;&gt;A reflection after Harvard College Israel Trek, a spring break trip I was fortunate enough to attend.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m back at Harvard now. It’s surreal and a little nostalgic to think that, rather than flurries of snow outside, we had desert heat bearing down on us just two weeks ago. Rather than red brick rising up around us and slush at our feet, we stood amidst pale Jerusalem stone and cats mewling on the streets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not that I’m &amp;lsquo;not prepared&amp;rsquo; to be back at school. I’m just craving a little more — more of what I was able to see, hear, feel, taste, touch and engage with over spring break. The Trek, made me appreciate how &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; there is out there in the world, and how interesting it all is. This should be a simple revelation, but it seems that every time I travel, I&amp;rsquo;m knocked over with the force of this sentiment as if I were learning it for the first time. (Or maybe gaining a deepening understanding of something feels almost the same as learning it afresh.) Two hops away by plane, I found incredibly diverse, rich lives humming away. Lives that I could only attempt to get close to and learn about during our short 10 days there, and ones that I found extremely difficult to define or generalize about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe what I’m trying to say is that things weren’t cohesive and tidy and my summary is not cohesive and tidy, and that’s just how it is. Israel/Palestine is not just a &amp;lsquo;conflict&amp;rsquo; or a &amp;lsquo;situation&amp;rsquo;. People live there, yes, despite everything. They have to. The Israel-Palestinian conflict has been a daily reality for decades, residing in the backs of minds and wearing its way into attitudes in both obvious and imperceptible ways. But then, it is a daily reality, so people grow around it and create realms outside of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are beautiful, straight-up people with uplifting attitudes that I miss, and a tapestry of landscapes that should belong to five different countries. There are Purim festivities where strangers will amiably compliment your purple tiger face paint, and hilariously absurd stories passed around of old Russian grandmothers and their American vacuum cleaners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrestled with and attempted to reconcile everything that I saw. Who are you? What’s your story? Why do you say the things that you do, and why are things the way that they are? How does the conflict play a role in this? Why does the conflict not play a role in this? It was a week of questioning, considering, evaluating, and running out of time. But even if I could have poked into every single speaker’s life, and dissected every person’s stories, the kind of satisfaction permitted by fitting a general solution, a thesis, or a conclusion&amp;mdash;of the kind we are taught to search for in class&amp;mdash;would still have eluded me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even in everyday life, there exist things that seem contradictory and incompatible. Israel is simultaneously a place for growing numbers of ultraorthodox Jews who decline to push elevator buttons on Shabbat, a place where gay pride flags flutter off Tel Aviv balconies, and a place where 19-year-old military kids run the most popular radio station, often using the airwaves to criticise the military itself. We visited a school for children of refugees and migrant workers, where the girls’ athletic team proudly competed for Israel at the Schools Olympic Games, despite difficulty getting through international borders, because the country they represented did not even permit them their requisite papers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The West Bank had its own surprises. I cannot deny the unease I felt driving through checkpoints into zones ominously marked A, B, or C, noticing rubbish littering the landscape, people with intimidatingly large guns staring at our bus, and settlements in the distance. Just having an inkling of the degree of conflict and anguish that has occurred and is occurring over the land I was on was unnerving. But it would be inaccurate to paint this as the whole picture. As we clambered off the bus in Ramallah, a sprawling lunch awaited us at a large, modern hotel, with beautiful Palestinian art on the walls. What kinds of travellers keep hotels like this in business?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And The Conflict itself — well, again, I didn’t walk away with a fleshed-out solution. Of course not. Old questions went unanswered and new questions arose. (For example, I’m still wondering how Israel can navigate being simultaneously Jewish and democratic.) Will signing a negotiation be healing in the way we hope? How much identity is tied up in hurt? Can we imagine Israel without a conflict with Palestine? Can we imagine Palestine without a conflict with Israel? Honestly, I’m not sure if this trip made me more or less inclined towards a career in international relations. Sometimes, political leadership and negotiation processes can be — simply put — the absolute pits, and sometimes, throwing more effort and people at a problem doesn’t seem to have an effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps my most valuable questions were not directed at the things I saw and the people I met. I also experienced uneasy moments of questioning myself. Upon arrival at a picturesque winery in Golan Heights, we learned of the contested nature of the region - which also happens to possess conditions described as “perfect” for winemaking. The fifty of us proceeded to taste and enjoy the products of vineyards that could only be planted after 250 burned-out tanks were cleared from the landscape after the Valley of Tears Battle. The grapes that grew over and upon the sites of battle and bloodshed coloured my beverage, and my perceptions. The wine-tasting experience was a giggly, delicious, entertaining affair — should I feel guilty for having fun? How should I conduct myself, with the knowledge that I have?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I have no verdicts. I did not experience the satisfaction of developing a neat, unified opinion about Israel. But then, all the most interesting and worthwhile questions to think about in life don’t have solid answers. Too often we are encouraged to quickly form opinions about a text we only just skimmed, a show we just saw, or the person we just met. Not having answers forces you to keep engaging, so perhaps arriving at answers shouldn’t be the ultimate goal of proposing questions. One thing I did learn for sure is that all of this starts and ends with people — and here I refer less to the complications of people than to the people you meet that inspire you (I think all fifty of us can say this about our tour guide Amir), the people that dance on table-tops beside you and the people that have three-hour dinner conversations with you. Their importance is one conclusion I can count on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>City of Contrasts</title>
      <link>https://saffronh.github.io/post/city-of-contrasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saffronh.github.io/post/city-of-contrasts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even just within the 5 days I&amp;rsquo;ve spent in Bangkok, I&amp;rsquo;ve seen so many different facets of this city. I&amp;rsquo;ve dined with a girl who spends all her time at malls and has a dad who shoots movies in Dubai. I&amp;rsquo;ve explored shopping malls (Siam Paragon, especially) targeted at the privileged, with gourmet food courts and McLarens parked in shiny exhibits on the fifth floor. But I&amp;rsquo;ve also wandered off into cramped, dusty side-streets, with crippled and blind folk shaking tin cups on the corner. Shacks fashioned from metal scraps teeter on the banks of the polluted river. In fact, most of the city reflects a country steeped in poverty and inequality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another interesting contrast I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed is that between the religious and the irreverent. Thailand is a Buddhist country, where one is expected to dress modestly and obey large warning signs advising tourists not to buy Buddha heads as decorations. Temples are a fixture in any itinerary; wandering through these elaborate structures, my jaw agape, has provided valuable insight into the ancient customs and beliefs that infuse the Thai way of life. The culture of reverential respect extends beyond religious deference - today, Catherine, Zhong and I wandered into a hospital/university with an enormous picture of the Thai king stretched across a building, and a monument beside which people were kneeling and praying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet, Thailand maintains an infamy that, I daresay, nobody would call pious. The city seems to wake up at night and one can enter into any manner of crazed debauchery possible. From the Patpong red light district to neon dildoes sold at streetside markets right beside Buddha miniatures, Thailand&amp;rsquo;s weird open-but-also-repressed impropriety is what makes it such an infamous destination for wacky stag parties and unforgettable nights out. Even simple things such as the number of transgender people I see around points to a country where people seem more free in their sexuality. However, sex tourism and trafficking are gigantic problems here. The thriving prostitution industry is actually only semi-legal and  badly regulated, and  worryingly, those girls are often in highly sketchy and dangerous situations that both the mass media and tourists choose to overlook for the sake of cheap entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, simply getting slightly lost will highlight the difference between &amp;ldquo;touristy&amp;rdquo; Bangkok and the locals&#39; actual everyday lives. I experienced the peak of such agony at Grand Palace, where I paid 500 THB to bake in 36 degree heat and be assaulted by swarms of people waving iPads, and street vendors conducting trade at excessive decibels, charging inflated prices for pomegranate juice and river cruises. In some ways this is hypocritical because the obvious fact is, I am a tourist too. But the vibe and claustrophobia of tourist traps are hard to bear. Yet in the multiple times that we have thrown away the figurative map (whether accidentally or on purpose) and meandered around the city, we have glimpsed far more valuable things for free. We have wandered through cramped sidewalk markets selling unfamiliar ingredients, tempted by stalls serving up deliciously fresh salads, noodle soups and desserts. Even just taking the water taxi (a fancy name for a public boat) and getting completely lost up the river showed us a dustier, more industrial, more residential facet of Bangkok. Wherever you are and wherever you&amp;rsquo;re heading, make it a point to get lost.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thirty-Six Frames</title>
      <link>https://saffronh.github.io/post/thirty-six-frames/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 23:56:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saffronh.github.io/post/thirty-six-frames/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sitting in my makeshift darkroom, I shut off the water spilling into the developing tank. My prize waits in its cocoon of chemicals. I uncoil the film, memories strangely unfamiliar in their plasticky permanence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Images accentuate life. A picture of soldiers tiptoeing through a dystopian battlefield was one of the earliest to lodge itself in my memory. This was &amp;ldquo;overseas&amp;rdquo;, I was told. So when Dad departed home to begin our new life &amp;ldquo;overseas&amp;rdquo;, I was utterly convinced that New Zealand would embody the visual hellscape I once saw on TV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My fears were quelled by new sights to the contrary—suburbs, pukekos, black sand beaches—when Mum and I packed our bags and landed. We never really unpacked. In the twelve years since, I&amp;rsquo;ve moved house ten times. As the restless years picked me up and dropped me off at new thresholds, I erased myself everyway from the places of my childhood. Best friends would melt, time and again, into memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With each new bedroom came a plethora of to-dos; new routines and busy parents left little room for reflection. Although I was in the habit of crisply punctuating every moment with my digital SLR camera, my past was no clearer to me for it. It was too easy to relentlessly snap away; abundance quashed &amp;ldquo;preservation&amp;rdquo; into a blurry, unending stream. If one picture speaks a thousand words, I carried millions of words all spoken at once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I inspect my memories for scratches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t care so much about these negatives if I hadn&amp;rsquo;t discovered Mum&amp;rsquo;s old Nikon and a solitary roll of film. I rationed that roll over a whole summer. I was a selective guardian of thirty-six tiny moments, able to etch my viewpoints into something tangible. As I selected, condensed, and haphazardly stitched together intermittent points in time, I practised deliberate reflection in specific moments. I grounded myself in reserving space for analogue in a shifting digital world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Film&amp;rsquo;s permanency is potent because it stores authenticity. I imagine the unfiltered light hitting the gelatine coating as directly imprinting people and emotions onto myself. Only the handpicked ones, that is. Perhaps paradoxically, this mindful sensitivity made me feel stronger and in control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I scan and examine the negatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this one, the apples on our tree are ripening in the backyard. My father holds a pumpkin up to the branches, chortling as if he happened upon it growing there. I crystallise the moment in silver halides, and every so often as the two of us sit down to dinner, I&amp;rsquo;ll think of that photo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next photo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upper Tama Lake greets me when I finally arrive, drenched wet and windburned. On the sixth and final day of our hike, a question had divided our group: Should we take the uphill scenic detour rather than a shower? Two hours later, the sight of the blue glass water urges me to always say, &amp;ldquo;Yes.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am in Queenstown snapping shots on a twilight walk, unknowingly blackening seven frames as the dusk sneaks in. In fact, my startled face darts out of the top corner of one underexposed picture. I designate these as experiments in refinement, not mistakes. Here, actual memory will have to suffice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Film has permitted me introspective reflection. This, in turn, has led to extroverted expression. The values and connotations I preserve on camera are channelled into future images as new perspectives. The frame doesn&amp;rsquo;t need or want me inside, yet it has always permitted self-expression within its walls. I can exhibit who and what I love within them: the squishy balls of stardust I call my friends, the tennis courts on which I drill serves like drumming a rhythm. That&amp;rsquo;s more me than my physical likeness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still shoot digital extensively, but usually for school events or art class projects. Film is my treat. Thirty-six frames were not made for indulgence, so I live first and photograph second. Every captured photon is a breath briefly bridging the linearity of time, asking me to observe and remember the moments that eventually constitute myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I load another roll into the camera for tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://saffronh.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saffronh.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello! I&amp;rsquo;m Saffron. I&amp;rsquo;m currently a research engineer at DeepMind. My research interests include language models, multi-agent RL and fairness &amp;amp; interpretability. I spend my free time dabbling, reading, writing, taking photographs, hiking, running and seeking out adventure. Current dabbles include creative writing, visual design, and computer history. I’m also currently on a grant to write about crypto and governance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I graduated in 2020 from Harvard with a degree in Applied Math-Computer Science. I got minors in Government and German (aber mein Deutsch ist schrecklich). I like to learn and think about AI and tech (and how they affect humans), political theory, China, economics, philosophy, among other things. Oh also, I grew up in New Zealand and am now London-based!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love meeting new people, so please feel free to reach out and say hi :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
