<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>travel on saffron huang</title>
    <link>https://saffronhuang.com/tags/travel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in travel on saffron huang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2016-19 &lt;a href=&#39;https://github.com/siegerts/hugo-theme-basic&#39;&gt;Hugo Theme Basic&lt;/a&gt;.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 23:56:59 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="https://saffronhuang.com/tags/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Art</title>
      <link>https://saffronhuang.com/post/creating-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 23:56:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saffronhuang.com/post/creating-art/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;written-during-my-summer-internship-in-berlin&#34;&gt;Written during my summer internship in Berlin.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every day I come home to my shared apartment in Prenzlauer Berg, I enter the living room to see Fabian on the balcony, grasping a hand-rolled cigarette and staring into the secluded courtyard that hides behind our apartment block.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll make dinner. Sometimes I’ll put in actual effort and sautée some sad-looking vegetable; other times I’ll eat a mixture of white rice and peanut butter with a spoon. He’ll still be there, soft jazzy beats bouncing from his cream-coloured Marshall amplifier. I’ll clean up, attempting to make the kitchen pristine enough to be photographed for sale tomorrow (an impressive ability to stay spotless and tidy on Ana and Fabian’s behalf). He’ll still be there, languidly inspecting his array of young bamboos and herbs, amongst which shoots of fake greenery have been placed to cover the gaps where gardening attempts went awry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I often wonder what he’s thinking about. I wonder how he can stay there for hours, appearing to doing nothing but chain-smoke. Does he ever feel unproductive? I wonder at what kind of contrast is occurring between the exterior and the interior. Maybe, since he is a psychiatrist on weekdays, he’s reflecting on what he’s seen at work, calming his mind. This nightly ritual could be a period of general reflection — perhaps on work, yes, but also life, family, relationships, politics. I have never asked him about it, though, and every time I come in from work he smiles and directs the focus onto me, “Wie war den Tag?” I feel as if I’ve wandered into his world and clumsily broken something every time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I came home to see pink graffiti scrawled on the glass balcony doors. Excess drips of neon paint meandered down the glass, through which I could see Fabian lounging on the balcony beside the cigarette papers and tobacco piles at the ready. This sudden “vandalism” gave the normally minimalist, white (and slightly sterile) aesthetic of the apartment a cheekiness that I never thought possible. “Did you do this?” I asked him, not wanting to make an incorrect assumption (perhaps its artist was Ana) since clearly, this occurence showed that my assumptions about others are so often wrong. Not &lt;em&gt;wrong&lt;/em&gt;, but wrong in the sense that they’re not generous enough to allow space to conceive them as creative beings with imaginations and impulses. I unconsciously categorize people too much; if they display their drawings and paintings on social media then they’re An Artist; I imagine that inexplicable Artistic Wheels are constantly spinning in their head, somehow churning out pretty visualisations that they translate through paints or 2B pencils or tablets. For Normal People, I become unreasonably surprised at seeing them exhibit the creativity that is really within us all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thursday was Ascension Day, a public holiday. I decided to take the U-Bahn to see The Haus, an exhibition on Nürnberger Straße. The TL;DR of the exhibit is: 160 artists locked into a 5-storey building, each artist gets to do whatever with their own room, building is destroyed on June 1st. I ended up waiting 4.5 (!!!) hours on a cold and windy spring day to see it. But I didn’t mind; the people in line in front of me jumped and danced for warmth with me, shared their mini Lindt pralines and strawberries with me, shouted me coffee, held my spot in line when I bought a chai latte to reverse the blue-ification of my lips, and talked to me about Berlin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most memorably, they pulled out miscellaneous sketchbooks and a roll of pencils of varying intensities, and sat in line sketching (former) strangers whilst conversing in German and laughing away the hours. First, the girl behind us with a nose ring, bright fabric headband and discerning blue eyes that looked on intently as they drew. Second, the man in front of us with a pink shirt, dark rectangular glasses and a closely-cropped head of silvering hair who seemed amused at the proceedings. I marvelled at how well one of them, a tall young man with dreadlocks and tortoiseshell glasses, drew and expressed that I wished I drew that well. He immediately responded, “You want to try?” and passed me a notebook and pencil. My pink-shirt-guy portrait wasn’t fantastic, and I hurried to make it bear some sort of resemblance as everyone else had almost finished theirs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A young couple in line with us were also bestowed simple drawing supplies, and we all happily drew on, sharing our works with lighthearted mmms and ahhhs. I’d assumed that the original group would all be fantastic artists, given their enthusiasm for sketching random people. A usual mindset of striving upwards, of always evaluating others and being evaluated for quality, modifies many things into a depersonalised show of skill — &lt;em&gt;like, are you &lt;strong&gt;good&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/em&gt; Again, I was unreasonably surprised that their works weren’t objectively spectacular. And so what? Art is for all to create. Berlin has taught me this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I saw his work, I asked of Fabian what “KEAM 1997” (two parts of the graffiti that I could actually discern) meant. He told me that he’d started painting graffiti as “KEAM” in 1997 — when he was 13. I thought of little 13-year-old Fabian picking up a spray can and laughed, “That’s the year I was born!” Perhaps a dumb little coincidence, but I thought of it it as a signal telling me, I should give it a go. He gave me the pink paint pen and taught me how to press so that liquid oozes and drips out as I mark out my design, and left me to my whims. I drew Pucci (their snowy, prickly-natured cat) and attempted some graffiti lettering. That was it. Nothing special happened before or after, I just picked up the pen and did it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Art-making is so easy and so &lt;em&gt;fun&lt;/em&gt;, but I attach such daunting significance to it, tying it to self-worth and significance and judgment. I assume that Artists possess inherent qualities of interestingness, mysteriousness and creativeness unable to be accessed or contemplated by Normal People such as myself. (I for some reason don&amp;rsquo;t seem to regard my own photography as Art.) Excessively esteeming people who create art elevates them into ideals and away from reality, and fabricates a personality divide where there isn’t one. The irony is that it is achingly simple to make art once you just stop contemplating it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could see Hugo looking at me intently. The bulky bandage gave him an enormous head. ‘The trouble with you, Jake,’ said Hugo, ‘is that you’re far too impressed by people. You were far too impressed by me.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was surprised. ‘I was impressed,’ I said, ‘but I didn’t know you knew.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘Everyone must go his own way, Jake,’ said Hugo. ‘Things don’t matter as much as you think.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;– &lt;em&gt;Iris Murdoch, Under The Net.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Absent Conclusions</title>
      <link>https://saffronhuang.com/post/absent-conclusions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2017 23:56:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saffronhuang.com/post/absent-conclusions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-reflection-after-harvard-college-israel-trek-a-spring-break-trip-i-was-fortunate-enough-to-attend&#34;&gt;A reflection after Harvard College Israel Trek, a spring break trip I was fortunate enough to attend.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m back at Harvard now. It’s surreal and a little nostalgic to think that, rather than flurries of snow outside, we had desert heat bearing down on us just two weeks ago. Rather than red brick rising up around us and slush at our feet, we stood amidst pale Jerusalem stone and cats mewling on the streets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not that I’m &amp;lsquo;not prepared&amp;rsquo; to be back at school. I’m just craving a little more — more of what I was able to see, hear, feel, taste, touch and engage with over spring break. The Trek, made me appreciate how &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; there is out there in the world, and how interesting it all is. This should be a simple revelation, but it seems that every time I travel, I&amp;rsquo;m knocked over with the force of this sentiment as if I were learning it for the first time. (Or maybe gaining a deepening understanding of something feels almost the same as learning it afresh.) Two hops away by plane, I found incredibly diverse, rich lives humming away. Lives that I could only attempt to get close to and learn about during our short 10 days there, and ones that I found extremely difficult to define or generalize about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe what I’m trying to say is that things weren’t cohesive and tidy and my summary is not cohesive and tidy, and that’s just how it is. Israel/Palestine is not just a &amp;lsquo;conflict&amp;rsquo; or a &amp;lsquo;situation&amp;rsquo;. People live there, yes, despite everything. They have to. The Israel-Palestinian conflict has been a daily reality for decades, residing in the backs of minds and wearing its way into attitudes in both obvious and imperceptible ways. But then, it is a daily reality, so people grow around it and create realms outside of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are beautiful, straight-up people with uplifting attitudes that I miss, and a tapestry of landscapes that should belong to five different countries. There are Purim festivities where strangers will amiably compliment your purple tiger face paint, and hilariously absurd stories passed around of old Russian grandmothers and their American vacuum cleaners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrestled with and attempted to reconcile everything that I saw. Who are you? What’s your story? Why do you say the things that you do, and why are things the way that they are? How does the conflict play a role in this? Why does the conflict not play a role in this? It was a week of questioning, considering, evaluating, and running out of time. But even if I could have poked into every single speaker’s life, and dissected every person’s stories, the kind of satisfaction permitted by fitting a general solution, a thesis, or a conclusion&amp;mdash;of the kind we are taught to search for in class&amp;mdash;would still have eluded me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even in everyday life, there exist things that seem contradictory and incompatible. Israel is simultaneously a place for growing numbers of ultraorthodox Jews who decline to push elevator buttons on Shabbat, a place where gay pride flags flutter off Tel Aviv balconies, and a place where 19-year-old military kids run the most popular radio station, often using the airwaves to criticise the military itself. We visited a school for children of refugees and migrant workers, where the girls’ athletic team proudly competed for Israel at the Schools Olympic Games, despite difficulty getting through international borders, because the country they represented did not even permit them their requisite papers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The West Bank had its own surprises. I cannot deny the unease I felt driving through checkpoints into zones ominously marked A, B, or C, noticing rubbish littering the landscape, people with intimidatingly large guns staring at our bus, and settlements in the distance. Just having an inkling of the degree of conflict and anguish that has occurred and is occurring over the land I was on was unnerving. But it would be inaccurate to paint this as the whole picture. As we clambered off the bus in Ramallah, a sprawling lunch awaited us at a large, modern hotel, with beautiful Palestinian art on the walls. What kinds of travellers keep hotels like this in business?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And The Conflict itself — well, again, I didn’t walk away with a fleshed-out solution. Of course not. Old questions went unanswered and new questions arose. (For example, I’m still wondering how Israel can navigate being simultaneously Jewish and democratic.) Will signing a negotiation be healing in the way we hope? How much identity is tied up in hurt? Can we imagine Israel without a conflict with Palestine? Can we imagine Palestine without a conflict with Israel? Honestly, I’m not sure if this trip made me more or less inclined towards a career in international relations. Sometimes, political leadership and negotiation processes can be — simply put — the absolute pits, and sometimes, throwing more effort and people at a problem doesn’t seem to have an effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps my most valuable questions were not directed at the things I saw and the people I met. I also experienced uneasy moments of questioning myself. Upon arrival at a picturesque winery in Golan Heights, we learned of the contested nature of the region - which also happens to possess conditions described as “perfect” for winemaking. The fifty of us proceeded to taste and enjoy the products of vineyards that could only be planted after 250 burned-out tanks were cleared from the landscape after the Valley of Tears Battle. The grapes that grew over and upon the sites of battle and bloodshed coloured my beverage, and my perceptions. The wine-tasting experience was a giggly, delicious, entertaining affair — should I feel guilty for having fun? How should I conduct myself, with the knowledge that I have?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I have no verdicts. I did not experience the satisfaction of developing a neat, unified opinion about Israel. But then, all the most interesting and worthwhile questions to think about in life don’t have solid answers. Too often we are encouraged to quickly form opinions about a text we only just skimmed, a show we just saw, or the person we just met. Not having answers forces you to keep engaging, so perhaps arriving at answers shouldn’t be the ultimate goal of proposing questions. One thing I did learn for sure is that all of this starts and ends with people — and here I refer less to the complications of people than to the people you meet that inspire you (I think all fifty of us can say this about our tour guide Amir), the people that dance on table-tops beside you and the people that have three-hour dinner conversations with you. Their importance is one conclusion I can count on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>City of Contrasts</title>
      <link>https://saffronhuang.com/post/city-of-contrasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saffronhuang.com/post/city-of-contrasts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even just within the 5 days I&amp;rsquo;ve spent in Bangkok, I&amp;rsquo;ve seen so many different facets of this city. I&amp;rsquo;ve dined with a girl who spends all her time at malls and has a dad who shoots movies in Dubai. I&amp;rsquo;ve explored shopping malls (Siam Paragon, especially) targeted at the privileged, with gourmet food courts and McLarens parked in shiny exhibits on the fifth floor. But I&amp;rsquo;ve also wandered off into cramped, dusty side-streets, with crippled and blind folk shaking tin cups on the corner. Shacks fashioned from metal scraps teeter on the banks of the polluted river. In fact, most of the city reflects a country steeped in poverty and inequality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another interesting contrast I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed is that between the religious and the irreverent. Thailand is a Buddhist country, where one is expected to dress modestly and obey large warning signs advising tourists not to buy Buddha heads as decorations. Temples are a fixture in any itinerary; wandering through these elaborate structures, my jaw agape, has provided valuable insight into the ancient customs and beliefs that infuse the Thai way of life. The culture of reverential respect extends beyond religious deference - today, Catherine, Zhong and I wandered into a hospital/university with an enormous picture of the Thai king stretched across a building, and a monument beside which people were kneeling and praying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet, Thailand maintains an infamy that, I daresay, nobody would call pious. The city seems to wake up at night and one can enter into any manner of crazed debauchery possible. From the Patpong red light district to neon dildoes sold at streetside markets right beside Buddha miniatures, Thailand&amp;rsquo;s weird open-but-also-repressed impropriety is what makes it such an infamous destination for wacky stag parties and unforgettable nights out. Even simple things such as the number of transgender people I see around points to a country where people seem more free in their sexuality. However, sex tourism and trafficking are gigantic problems here. The thriving prostitution industry is actually only semi-legal and  badly regulated, and  worryingly, those girls are often in highly sketchy and dangerous situations that both the mass media and tourists choose to overlook for the sake of cheap entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, simply getting slightly lost will highlight the difference between &amp;ldquo;touristy&amp;rdquo; Bangkok and the locals&#39; actual everyday lives. I experienced the peak of such agony at Grand Palace, where I paid 500 THB to bake in 36 degree heat and be assaulted by swarms of people waving iPads, and street vendors conducting trade at excessive decibels, charging inflated prices for pomegranate juice and river cruises. In some ways this is hypocritical because the obvious fact is, I am a tourist too. But the vibe and claustrophobia of tourist traps are hard to bear. Yet in the multiple times that we have thrown away the figurative map (whether accidentally or on purpose) and meandered around the city, we have glimpsed far more valuable things for free. We have wandered through cramped sidewalk markets selling unfamiliar ingredients, tempted by stalls serving up deliciously fresh salads, noodle soups and desserts. Even just taking the water taxi (a fancy name for a public boat) and getting completely lost up the river showed us a dustier, more industrial, more residential facet of Bangkok. Wherever you are and wherever you&amp;rsquo;re heading, make it a point to get lost.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
