<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>school on saffron huang</title>
    <link>https://saffronh.github.io/tags/school/</link>
    <description>Recent content in school on saffron huang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2016-19 &lt;a href=&#39;https://github.com/siegerts/hugo-theme-basic&#39;&gt;Hugo Theme Basic&lt;/a&gt;.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="https://saffronh.github.io/tags/school/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtually Social</title>
      <link>https://saffronh.github.io/post/virtually-social/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saffronh.github.io/post/virtually-social/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“I’m sorry I can’t make section today,” I thumbed into my phone, four minutes before class was due to start. “I had thought it might be difficult to paint outdoors at this time because it’s sunrise here, and the light keeps changing, but on top of that it’s now raining. Can I do the painting later?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The email whizzed off. I made coffee and looked out the window. The droplets were mistier now, and the sun had almost wiped out the baby-pink streaks of dawn with fully-fledged rays. Maybe I could just get through the work now, rather than have the task (&amp;ldquo;Studio Assignment #8: Plein Air Painting&amp;rdquo;) sit on my mind for the next few days. Aurora pinged me back, consenting to my absence from class. I deliberated, gathered my brushes in the name of anti-procrastination and propped a gessoed canvas up in the backyard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ten minutes into tracing the edges of three empty pots in the crusted vegetable garden, I remembered that section was still happening over Zoom. Should I dial in? The inertia of my solitude groaned somewhere inside my body. I thought about the feeling of surveilling and being surveilled by pixellated classmates, and went on mixing paint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After we’d been sent home in the middle of the semester, Matt and Aurora had done their best to keep our painting studio class edifying and enjoyable. Four days into my post-arrival quarantine at home, a large square package reached my door containing four canvases, paper, oil paints, gesso, solvent and extra brushes. I found the receipt in the box, realised how much they’d spent on me, and felt tired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first painting class I’ve taken. Three days after an email notified us to leave campus, I rolled up my splotchy paintings in my suitcase, worrying that this gratifying experiment had met its end. Physically splintering apart could twist this studio class so completely that, even with a personal tub of gesso mailed to my door, it was over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past month, our painting section had morphed from studio time to breakout room discussions of each other&amp;rsquo;s photographed work. This week was actually unusual in that we&amp;rsquo;d attempt to return to live painting, and to evoke the coworking space that we&amp;rsquo;d had before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like having a routine to slide me out of solitude. Walking to class listening to music or coaxing the key out of the door gets me ready for public spaces, for giving and receiving attention. It’s like the feeling of grinding coffee in your pyjamas, the beans nudging your dozing nose awake for another day of breathing. I dread the cold-water shock of joining group calls; the sudden surveillance of a webcam is too rude. The thought of dialing in to section 15 minutes late was too weary to entertain, until guilt took over and I picked up my phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I get a similar feeling whenever I click on the link to attend my English seminar. I love this class, and the way it feels like book club, but it now requires 3:52am alarms (noon in Boston is four in the morning in New Zealand) and focusing my straggling attention on flat little people in flat little boxes on my screen for two-and-a-half hours. I’ll watch my professor explaining some line from &lt;em&gt;Effi Briest&lt;/em&gt;, and imagine trying to figure out if the 23 muted faces, eyes directed somewhere unknowable, understood your take on the merits of Mr. and Mrs. Briest&amp;rsquo;s parenting style. I imagine not getting any feedback from the usual shuffling feet or coughing, and wondering whether the connection might have broken during a critical pedagogical moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now he’s joking about people tuning out, and I anxiously raise my eyebrows at the computer—attentively, I hope—to stem the virtual awkwardness. Look, someone is paying attention to you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not such an eager student in other classes. The first week I had my video on in my quantum lecture. Only one other person did. I committed, stubbornly, to keeping the camera on. The norms for virtual attention were still malleable, I thought, and I didn’t want the professor to feel abandoned by default.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second week, I’d quickly learned that I was not influential enough to change virtual classroom norms, and anyway, the administrators had decided to change the grading status of all classes to a universal pass/fail system. I switched the camera off, rolled out my yoga mat, and spent lecture stretching on the floor. Barely listening, I played a round of minigolf on my phone with a friend, thinking absent-mindedly about how all the difficulties of the game were missing in its digital manifestation — you didn’t have to remind yourself to use the right power, swing your arms just enough, don’t forget to maintain the angle. Everything had lost its physicality recently; minigolf was just another example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I looked up from my screens, I’d become distracted by the immense dimensionality that exists in the physical environment. Reflections in a fork! Puckered leaves on a basil plant! Does anyone else ever think about throwing their laptop into the bushes and running away from a life of pixels?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the class, I unmuted myself. In my best casually-enthusiastic voice I projected &lt;em&gt;Thank you!&lt;/em&gt; into the microphone and left as quickly as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Virtual socializing has its intimacies. I no longer meet people in neutral public settings in which we follow the norms of being a guest in a third space. No more coffee catch-ups during which jazzy café music and indifferent baristas subconsciously prompt us towards a familiar mode of public behaviour. Now, we exclusively show up in our homes, implicitly giving every single person we meet a tour of our most private spaces. I see nice headphones and cats walking across keyboards. They see the titles on my bookshelf and the dramatically green desk my dad bought me in high school. Professors and acquaintances can read my space, deduce that I&amp;rsquo;m messy. My sister bursts in to call me to dinner, even though I texted her that I was on an important call.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Public and private have inverted, and finally melted together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are the new norms we&amp;rsquo;re establishing? How are we behaving now?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was scheduled to participate in some informational visits to various organisations in the Bay Area before COVID-19 really hit. Instead of seeing industry leaders lecturing in their offices, I saw the family photos on their coffee tables. One prominent researcher apologised for the presence of an absurdly massive panda floatie propped behind his shoulder; he was using it to block the sun’s glare through the window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would have been so easy to take a screenshot of him and his inflatable panda with the creepy eyes—that&amp;rsquo;s the thing with digital interactions, you never know which of your footprints others are keeping—but it felt like he was investing in us an unanticipated trust, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to fracture the intimacy of our understanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a specific angle that I never used to see people from — throat-first, upward-tilted. Now I see those tipped, exposed faces all the time from the fixed viewpoint of the webcam. It&amp;rsquo;s accentuated by furrowed brows as people look for the unmute button, blurred cheeks as they hurry through their living room. I never asked for this particular intimacy from others, nor did they ask for mine. It just fell on us circumstantially.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some days I love the limited interactions and the focused, quiet lifestyle I&amp;rsquo;m developing. I don’t have to engage in a social performance if I’d rather curl up in my thoughts. Other days I crave running into a friend at Peets and chatting about an upcoming concert, and I can&amp;rsquo;t quite stomach how different virtual conversations are from those accidental hellos. I plead with my brain to forget about that for a few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often, I can only find out how introverted I&amp;rsquo;m feeling through having that online social interaction I&amp;rsquo;m being indecisive about. When I virtually entered the painting class, I sensed tranquility. No one was speaking. Some people had their microphone &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; their video off. My shoulders loosened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I settled down and scraped burnt umber and ultramarine blue together with a palette knife as my classmates worked quietly, moving across my phone screen. It&amp;rsquo;s funny how a single sun can manifest as late afternoon rays on some pixellated faces and, at the same instant, as a feeble morning glow on others who haven&amp;rsquo;t quite reached that point in the day yet. A cricket chirped somewhere in cyberspace, and I heard it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In retrospect, perhaps I should have known that this class would not exhaust my attention in the same punishing way that others tended to. We were gathered online to work alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I wanted to ask something about lecture,” Emily, another senior, began. Matt gave her the go-ahead. Abstract Expressionism (this was the topic of his most recent lecture) is often the movement that people point to when they talk of the moment that art became pretentious. People don&amp;rsquo;t look at Renaissance paintings and say that, really. What was his response to that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wind rustled through a tree somewhere in San Diego.  Solvent swished in Cambridge. I dabbed at my canvas with a caked paper towel, agreeing with Emily in my head. Matt mused on the question, said she was broadly right about that impression, ahh’d a bit about his opinion, and asked Aurora for hers.  She, too, seemed uncertain. “It’s hard to justify making anything,” she said finally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amidst the ebb and flow of sighs and swishes and occasional questions, I would find inspiration in one sound or another, each pulling me into a new well of thought. I floated in the pools in my head, without feeling the usual obligation to climb out of the water and begin the effort of camouflaging the gap between this and The Normal Class Experience We Should Be Having using attentive-looking smiles and thumbs-up emojis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were hearing, feeling, painting together. A shared experience consolidated in virtual snippets of reality and unexpected abstractions, rather than the physical space of the studio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I unfolded my legs and turned off the microphone and camera on my phone, then went inside to make a snack. As I stared at the closed blinds of the kitchen window, munching on a peanut butter and banana sandwich, birdsong emanated from the phone in my pocket. It sounded like someone was dialing in from a forest. I didn’t check to see who, just contentedly let another reality fill my ears. So many guessing games, so many unknowns — opportunities for speculation hid in every corner of a virtual interaction. Perhaps the birdsong broadcaster was unaware that they had their microphone on, or maybe they knew perfectly well that they’d set off ten different trains of thought (about bluejays or avian migration patterns or something else) chugging around the world. Maybe someone did suspect that I’d abandoned painting in favour of eating in the middle of class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The professor’s keyboard clacked. The cyber cricket crooned, and the birds went on. I stood at the kitchen sink, letting the sounds from other people’s realities fill my own, become my own.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elite Disillusionment</title>
      <link>https://saffronh.github.io/post/elite-disillusionment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 23:56:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saffronh.github.io/post/elite-disillusionment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All manner of people take all manner of issue with elite universities. Chief among the usual qualms is the observation that places like Harvard pump out more &lt;a href=&#34;https://features.thecrimson.com/2019/senior-survey/after-harvard/&#34;&gt;financial analysts and consultants&lt;/a&gt; than &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thecrimson.com/article/2014/11/6/consulting-after-harvard-fm/&#34;&gt;appropriate&lt;/a&gt; for a university that purports to educate the &lt;a href=&#34;https://college.harvard.edu/about/mission-vision-history&#34;&gt;transformative citizen-leaders&lt;/a&gt; of tomorrow. Is this really what all these kids came here to do, and why does the mission seem to fall so short? As I reach the tail end of my time here, I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about the distinct ways I&amp;rsquo;ve seen this environment &amp;ndash; with all its trappings, narratives, and institutions &amp;ndash; shape student paths. Sometimes I joke that Harvard is gaslighting all of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;magnificent-dreams&#34;&gt;magnificent dreams&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You get into Harvard by wanting to change the world, by having pie-in-the-sky ambitions. You don&amp;rsquo;t get in by limiting your goals simply to college admission - or, at least, you render that ulterior aim of yours undetectable. On the whole, it has been my experience that Harvard does manage to admit a lot of amazing, well-intentioned, bright people. But it changes them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People get there, and realise that they&amp;rsquo;re not the best, the smartest, or the most hard-working anymore. So they say, okay, my role is not to change the world. That&amp;rsquo;s the role of him, or her, or them, because they&amp;rsquo;re all smarter and more hard-working than I am. The kid who just patented an invention, the other one who wrote two books, and the countless NGO founders who have collectively raised millions of dollars as teenagers. The &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; innovators, with destiny. Although these are largely illusory narratives and impressions, psychologically, their place in the world shifts. People become much less ambitious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They start to think smaller, safer. &lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not good enough for magnificent dreams. Hell, I can&amp;rsquo;t even get into any clubs.&lt;/em&gt; (Exclusivity is a bit of an issue on this campus.) &lt;em&gt;Anyway, how do I even &amp;lsquo;change the world&amp;rsquo; as I&amp;rsquo;d promised everyone upon entry to this place? I&amp;rsquo;m here now and I need to start fulfilling that mission, but man, people don&amp;rsquo;t talk about the logistics.&lt;/em&gt; The scope of their dreams tighten, from can-do-anything to yikes-I&amp;rsquo;m-not-THAT-exceptional-let&amp;rsquo;s-just-climb-the-ladder-that&amp;rsquo;s-meant-for-me. There &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; that guaranteed, successful thing that still impresses people and satisfies parents, but doesn&amp;rsquo;t change anything of substance. As luck would have it, that&amp;rsquo;s exactly the sort of path that career offices tend to be talented at finding and providing &amp;ndash; the stable and prestigious opportunities at firms willing to pay &lt;a href=&#34;https://perma.cc/CP96-3AVH&#34;&gt;up to $18,000&lt;/a&gt; to recruit at career fairs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first two years, when people asked me what I wanted to do with my education, I&amp;rsquo;d think back to the massive fantasies I&amp;rsquo;d concocted in my bedroom as a 17-year-old in Auckland, and feel a bit silly remembering the vague and grandiose notion of changing the world that had underpinned my aims. I mean, I&amp;rsquo;d had more specific ideas than that, but to tell the truth, the only thing I had real confidence in was that I wanted to &lt;em&gt;really contribute something&lt;/em&gt;. I still did, and do. But having control of your life isn&amp;rsquo;t something that just happens to you; you have to be pro-active about it. And at times when I felt swamped with homework* I&amp;rsquo;d grumble to myself that it felt like Harvard was actively preventing me from figuring out what I really should be doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be hugely helpful if students had more breathing room and headspace, or ways to talk about and normalise these thoughts, and collaborate to make their dreams slightly less vague. Likewise, it would go a long way if career services had more resources on strategic decision-making and calculated risk-taking, or access to mentorship from people in &amp;ldquo;non-traditional&amp;rdquo; pathways. There is a lot of underexplored room for improvement in how we guide our young people, and significant mismatches in the labour market as a result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There seems to be a lot of low-hanging fruit and potential for high ROI for solutions in this area. Career choices are some of the most important decisions people make, yet convention expects them to start narrowing down their path early on with very little information or experience trying things out, to prepare years in advance without knowing what the demand for various jobs or skills might be by the time they graduate, to listen to out-of-date advice, to conduct their first job-search almost exclusively within the narrow scope of the companies that choose to recruit at their school, and to place no emphasis on seriously sitting down to forecast how the future might look in 20-30 years when you&amp;rsquo;re mid-career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;uprooted&#34;&gt;uprooted&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By going to college for four years, you become uprooted from your home and community, and lose significant agency and power to serve a community that you know and are committed to. I personally got very disconnected from New Zealand while away &amp;ndash; I felt like I didn&amp;rsquo;t have my finger on the pulse of the place anymore, didn&amp;rsquo;t know what was happening &amp;ndash; and it&amp;rsquo;s hard to replace that with a new town in a new country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who should you be making a change for, what do you invest in, when you&amp;rsquo;re in an inherently transitory position? It&amp;rsquo;s obviously not impossible to do so, but it&amp;rsquo;s a difficulty that many don&amp;rsquo;t anticipate, especially if you&amp;rsquo;re someone that&amp;rsquo;s interested in sustainable, direct and local impact. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to imagine taking up responsibilities in Cambridge community development or the local council, if you know you&amp;rsquo;re only there 26 weeks a year for four years. Although there are plenty of people who volunteer as tutors, mentors and so on, I think the transience pushes many people to focus on self-development instead (including myself). This is completely fine, as personal growth is obviously important, but constant absorption in the self might be teaching students not to prioritise other-regarding goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;psychological-doors&#34;&gt;psychological doors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elite colleges also actually close doors &amp;ndash; at least, psychologically. You don&amp;rsquo;t see Harvard alumni becoming plumbers, or farmers, or opening a corner store, or doing things that aren&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;worthy&amp;rdquo; of their degree, even if that&amp;rsquo;s what makes them happy. The pressure to prove that the price tag and hard work was &amp;ldquo;worth it&amp;rdquo;, and that you &amp;ldquo;lived up to your potential&amp;rdquo;, is an insidious side effect of attendance that no one talks about. It&amp;rsquo;s another barrier to risk-taking &amp;ndash; even though they have an elite degree, which is ironically one of the best career backup plans one could possibly have. (And yes, I acknowledge that this is a privileged problem; it is still a problem.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find that people back home are often &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; more ambitious about changing their part of the world than people at Harvard. At the end of sophomore year I felt blown away at how many Auckland University kids I knew that were starting companies and social enterprises, creating maker spaces, doing art, running for council &amp;ndash; and nonchalantly inventing their own rules, which is something Harvard kids don&amp;rsquo;t seem to do. It might be that they don&amp;rsquo;t harbour so much mental pressure. It might be that they don&amp;rsquo;t take everything so seriously. It might be that they&amp;rsquo;re not so paralysed by and unaccustomed to the idea of failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The obligatory disclaimer is that I am grateful beyond words for my college education, which has permitted me the most eye-opening and irreplaceable experiences. Nevertheless, I like to think of myself as a realist about the kind of place Harvard is, and the spectrum of effects it has on people. There is much impact to be had in solving some of these problems, and in creating environments for college students in which they are empowered to take the risks they want to (especially if they are very well-placed to take risks), have agency, and can more easily find networks of others wanting to be creative and inspired, to create a mutually-reinforcing spiral of creativeness and inspiration until everyone explodes in a burst of glitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, elite schools open doors, but it&amp;rsquo;s about what you do with your education regardless of where or if you attend college. And (my main point) it&amp;rsquo;s about whether your mind is free from all the new narratives and pressures, finding ways past potential disillusionment and isolation to create connections, to do scary things and to breathe life into the dreams that you seek. I&amp;rsquo;ve found it to be a fulfilling experience, and I&amp;rsquo;m thankful that I currently feel no less ambitious than I did before. It hasn&amp;rsquo;t been an easy or wholly happy ride &amp;ndash; but one that has forced me to figure out what I actually care about (which is continuously a work in progress). If you make sure that you don&amp;rsquo;t lose yourself in the madness, you really can find yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;* As some who know me will have heard me complain, homework comprising 70% of one&amp;rsquo;s semester grade was something entirely new to me at the start of college. I thought that homework was a learning aid, to help you as you went along and started really understanding the material and putting it all together in your head. Unfortunately, it&amp;rsquo;s mostly just a weekly stressor (or in the case of one of my first-year maths classes, 3x a week, each due at 9am) that you have to get basically perfect without fail, if you have any hope of getting an A. Everyone spends all their time nit-picking tricky and specific details rather than ensuring that they have a deep comprehension of the material&amp;hellip; (When you have three problem sets per week, and a host of other things to deal with in your academic/extracurricular/social life, it&amp;rsquo;s funny how myopic your education can become)&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elite Disillusionment (Annotated)</title>
      <link>https://saffronh.github.io/post/elite-disillusionment-annotated/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 02:56:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saffronh.github.io/post/elite-disillusionment-annotated/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;After drafting, I sent this to a few people, including my good friend &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/matthewdsun&#34;&gt;Matt Sun&lt;/a&gt; who made some insightful comments, drawing from his Stanford experience. I love to put pieces in conversation and see what emerges, so asked him to share those comments, which he kindly agreed to do. You are reading the annotated version of this (other version is &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;here&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;). I would be interested in seeing whether others (you?) have thoughts on these topics too. Also, this piece inspired a much longer and much more biting &lt;a href=&#34;https://palladiummag.com/2020/07/27/harvard-creates-managers-instead-of-elites/&#34;&gt;analysis&lt;/a&gt; of elite education I wrote for Palladium Magazine.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All manner of people take all manner of issue with elite universities. Chief among the usual qualms is the observation that places like Harvard pump out more &lt;a href=&#34;https://features.thecrimson.com/2019/senior-survey/after-harvard/&#34;&gt;financial analysts and consultants&lt;/a&gt; than &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thecrimson.com/article/2014/11/6/consulting-after-harvard-fm/&#34;&gt;appropriate&lt;/a&gt; for a university that purports to educate the &lt;a href=&#34;https://college.harvard.edu/about/mission-vision-history&#34;&gt;transformative citizen-leaders&lt;/a&gt; of tomorrow. Is this really what all these kids came here to do, and why does the mission seem to fall so short? As I reach the tail end of my time here, I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about the distinct ways I&amp;rsquo;ve seen this environment &amp;ndash; with all its trappings, narratives, and institutions &amp;ndash; shape student paths. Sometimes I joke that Harvard is gaslighting all of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;magnificent-dreams&#34;&gt;magnificent dreams&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You get into Harvard by wanting to change the world, by having pie-in-the-sky ambitions. You don&amp;rsquo;t get in by limiting your goals simply to college admission - or, at least, you render that ulterior aim of yours undetectable. On the whole, it has been my experience that Harvard does manage to admit a lot of amazing, well-intentioned, bright people. But it changes them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People get there, and &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;realise that they&amp;rsquo;re not the best, the smartest, or the most hard-working anymore.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
So they say, okay, my role is not to change the world. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s the role of him, or her, or them, because they&amp;rsquo;re all smarter and more hard-working than I am.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; The kid who just patented an invention, the other one who wrote two books, and the countless NGO founders who have collectively raised millions of dollars as teenagers. The &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; innovators, with destiny. Although these are largely illusory narratives and impressions, psychologically, their place in the world shifts. People become much less ambitious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They start to think smaller, safer. &lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not good enough for magnificent dreams. Hell, I can&amp;rsquo;t even get into any clubs.&lt;/em&gt; (Exclusivity is a bit of an issue on this campus.) &lt;em&gt;Anyway, how do I even &amp;lsquo;change the world&amp;rsquo; as I&amp;rsquo;d promised everyone upon entry to this place? I&amp;rsquo;m here now and I need to start fulfilling that mission, but man, people don&amp;rsquo;t talk about the logistics.&lt;/em&gt; The scope of their dreams tighten, from can-do-anything to yikes-I&amp;rsquo;m-not-THAT-exceptional-let&amp;rsquo;s-just-climb-the-ladder-that&amp;rsquo;s-meant-for-me. There &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; that guaranteed, successful thing that still impresses people and satisfies parents, but doesn&amp;rsquo;t change anything of substance. As luck would have it, that&amp;rsquo;s exactly the sort of path that career offices tend to be talented at finding and providing &amp;ndash; the stable and prestigious opportunities at firms willing to pay &lt;a href=&#34;https://perma.cc/CP96-3AVH&#34;&gt;up to $18,000&lt;/a&gt; to recruit at career fairs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first two years, when people asked me what I wanted to do with my education, I&amp;rsquo;d think back to the massive fantasies I&amp;rsquo;d concocted in my bedroom as a 17-year-old in Auckland, and feel a bit silly remembering the vague and grandiose notion of changing the world that had underpinned my aims. I mean, I&amp;rsquo;d had more specific ideas than that, but to tell the truth, the only thing I had real confidence in was that I wanted to &lt;em&gt;really contribute something&lt;/em&gt;. I still did, and do. But having control of your life isn&amp;rsquo;t something that just happens to you; you have to be pro-active about it. And at times when I felt swamped with homework* I&amp;rsquo;d grumble to myself that it felt like Harvard was actively preventing me from figuring out what I really should be doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be hugely helpful if students had more breathing room and headspace, or ways to talk about and normalise these thoughts, and collaborate to make their dreams slightly less vague. Likewise, it would go a long way if career services had more resources on strategic decision-making and calculated risk-taking, or access to mentorship from people in &amp;ldquo;non-traditional&amp;rdquo; pathways. There is a lot of underexplored room for improvement in how we guide our young people, and significant mismatches in the labour market as a result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There seems to be a lot of low-hanging fruit and potential for high ROI for solutions in this area. Career choices are some of the most important decisions people make, yet convention expects them to start narrowing down their path early on with very little information or experience trying things out, to prepare years in advance without knowing what the demand for various jobs or skills might be by the time they graduate, to listen to out-of-date advice, to conduct their first job-search almost exclusively within the narrow scope of the companies that choose to recruit at their school, and to place no emphasis on seriously sitting down to forecast how the future might look in 20-30 years when you&amp;rsquo;re mid-career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;uprooted&#34;&gt;uprooted&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By going to college for four years, you become uprooted from your home and community, and lose significant agency and power to serve a community that you know and are committed to. I personally got very disconnected from New Zealand while away &amp;ndash; I felt like I didn&amp;rsquo;t have my finger on the pulse of the place anymore, didn&amp;rsquo;t know what was happening &amp;ndash; and it&amp;rsquo;s hard to replace that with a new town in a new country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who should you be making a change for, what do you invest in, when you&amp;rsquo;re in an inherently transitory position? It&amp;rsquo;s obviously not impossible to do so, but it&amp;rsquo;s a difficulty that many don&amp;rsquo;t anticipate, especially if you&amp;rsquo;re someone that&amp;rsquo;s interested in sustainable, direct and local impact. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to imagine taking up responsibilities in Cambridge community development or the local council, if you know you&amp;rsquo;re only there 26 weeks a year for four years. Although there are plenty of people who volunteer as tutors, mentors and so on, I think the transience pushes many people to focus on self-development instead (including myself). &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;This is completely fine, as personal growth is obviously important, but constant absorption in the self might be teaching students not to prioritise other-regarding goals.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;psychological-doors&#34;&gt;psychological doors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elite colleges also actually close doors &amp;ndash; at least, psychologically. You don&amp;rsquo;t see Harvard alumni becoming plumbers, or farmers, or opening a corner store, or doing things that aren&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;worthy&amp;rdquo; of their degree, even if that&amp;rsquo;s what makes them happy. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;The pressure to prove that the price tag and hard work was &amp;ldquo;worth it&amp;rdquo;, and that you &amp;ldquo;lived up to your potential&amp;rdquo;, is an insidious side effect of attendance that no one talks about.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s another barrier to risk-taking &amp;ndash; even though they have an elite degree, which is ironically one of the best career backup plans one could possibly have. (And yes, I acknowledge that this is a privileged problem; it is still a problem.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find that people back home are often &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; more ambitious about changing their part of the world than people at Harvard. At the end of sophomore year I felt blown away at how many Auckland University kids I knew that were starting companies and social enterprises, creating maker spaces, doing art, running for council &amp;ndash; and nonchalantly inventing their own rules, which is something Harvard kids don&amp;rsquo;t seem to do. It might be that they don&amp;rsquo;t harbour so much mental pressure. It might be that they don&amp;rsquo;t take everything so seriously. It might be that they&amp;rsquo;re not so paralysed by and unaccustomed to the idea of failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The obligatory disclaimer is that I am grateful beyond words for my college education, which has permitted me the most eye-opening and irreplaceable experiences. Nevertheless, I like to think of myself as a realist about the kind of place Harvard is, and the spectrum of effects it has on people. There is much impact to be had in solving some of these problems, and in creating environments for college students in which they are empowered to take the risks they want to (especially if they are very well-placed to take risks), have agency, and can more easily find networks of others wanting to be creative and inspired, to create a mutually-reinforcing spiral of creativeness and inspiration until everyone explodes in a burst of glitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, elite schools open doors, but it&amp;rsquo;s about what you do with your education regardless of where or if you attend college. And (my main point) it&amp;rsquo;s about whether your mind is free from all the new narratives and pressures, finding ways past potential disillusionment and isolation to create connections, to do scary things and to breathe life into the dreams that you seek. I&amp;rsquo;ve found it to be a fulfilling experience, and I&amp;rsquo;m thankful that I currently feel no less ambitious than I did before. It hasn&amp;rsquo;t been an easy or wholly happy ride &amp;ndash; but one that has forced me to figure out what I actually care about (which is continuously a work in progress). If you make sure that you don&amp;rsquo;t lose yourself in the madness, you really can find yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;* As some who know me will have heard me complain, homework comprising 70% of one&amp;rsquo;s semester grade was something entirely new to me at the start of college. I thought that homework was a learning aid, to help you as you went along and started really understanding the material and putting it all together in your head. Unfortunately, it&amp;rsquo;s mostly just a weekly stressor (or in the case of one of my first-year maths classes, 3x a week, each due at 9am) that you have to get basically perfect without fail, if you have any hope of getting an A. Everyone spends all their time nit-picking tricky and specific details rather than ensuring that they have a deep comprehension of the material&amp;hellip; (When you have three problem sets per week, and a host of other things to deal with in your academic/extracurricular/social life, it&amp;rsquo;s funny how myopic your education can become)&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
